科尔顿·奥格登：大家好
COLTON OGDEN: Hi, everybody.
我的名字是科尔顿·奥格登 这是GD50第一课
My name is Colton Ogden, and this is GD50 lecture one,
今天我们将报道Flappy Bird
and today we'll be covering Flappy Bird.
所以去年或上周 抱歉 我们报道了乒乓球
So last year or last week, sorry, we covered Pong,
这只是基本的形状和颜色
which was just basic shapes and colors.
今天 我们将真正潜入精灵之中
Today we'll actually be diving into sprites.
正如我们在这里看到的 我们有一些管子和一只鸟
As we can see here, we've got some pipes, and a bird,
我们还讨论了其他一些概念 如重力等
and we're covering a few other concepts such as gravity, and more.
今天 我们将涵盖的主题简而言之就是图像和精灵
Today, the topics that we'll be covering are in a nutshell, images and sprites,
就像我刚才说的
as I just said.
因此 从我们的硬盘中加载内存中的图像
So loading images from memory from our hard drive,
并将它们绘制到屏幕上 而不仅仅是矩形
and actually drawing them to the screen instead of just rectangles,
诸如此类的
and whatnot.
我们将覆盖无限滚动
We'll be covering infinite scrolling.
所以 如果你玩过这个游戏
So seeing things like-- and if you've played the game,
管道无限地从右向左延伸
pipes are infinitely going from right to left.
如何真正让它无限地进行 这样我们就不会
How to actually get that going infinitely so that we're not
也会耗尽无限的内存
using up also infinite memory.
我们将以类似的方式讨论游戏是如何
We'll be discussing how games, and in the similar vein,
是幻觉 从某种意义上说 许多感知到的浩瀚和感知
are illusions in the sense that a lot of the perceived vastness and perceived
游戏的复杂性往往只是由于相机的诡计
complexity of games is often just due to camera trickery,
更多的原因是有限的硬件
and more because of limited hardware.
我们将介绍程序生成 它
We'll be covering procedural generation, which
纽带还可以无限滚动
ties also into infinite scrolling.
程序生成其实是我非常感兴趣的一个话题
Procedure generation is a topic that I am actually very interested in,
并将在整个课程中在几个地点涉及到它
and will be touching on it throughout the course in several locations.
但在今天的演讲中 我们将用它来制作管道
But in the context of today's lecture, we'll be using it for the pipes
因为管子 它们在Flappy Bird中从右到左繁殖
because the pipes, they spawn from right to left in Flappy Bird
当你无限地通过关卡的时候
as you're infinitely going through the level,
但它们可以在不同的高度产卵
but they can spawn at various heights, and the gaps
正因为如此而移动 因此创造了这个无限的水平
are shifting as a result of that, therefore creating this infinite level.
我们将更详细地讨论状态机
We'll be talking more in detail on state machines.
因此 上周我们以非常抽象的方式介绍了状态机
So last week we covered state machines in a very abstract sense.
我们基本上只使用一个字符串作为变量 然后使用if条件
We used just basically a string as a variable, and then used if conditions.
今天我们将实际使用状态机
Today we'll be actually using a state machine
用各种方法填充的类 这些方法允许
class replete with various methods that allow
美国在这些州的进进出出
us to transition in and out of these states very
干净利落地 让我们打破所有这些逻辑
cleanly, and allow us to break out all of this logic
我们以前在更新和渲染函数中拥有的
that we previously had in our update and render functions,
然后把它们分别放在各自的州立班级中
and then put them separately into their own state classes.
最后 我们还将讨论鼠标输入
And then lastly, we'll also be touching on mouse input.
还有一点是我忘了在这里提的
And a point that I forgot to mention here,
哎呀 我们还会讨论音乐 这基本上就是
whoops, is also we'll be talking about music, which is just basically
听起来像我们上周做的那样
sound, which we did last week.
但我们将添加这一点作为润色
But we'll add that as a polishing touch.
如果你们想下载演示代码的话
If you guys want to download the demo code.
我们现在在GitHub/Games50/五十鸟上有回购
We have a repo up right now on GitHub/games50/fiftybirds.
这是我们对Flappy Bird的看法
It's our take on Flappy Bird.
有几件事 我被问了几次
A couple of things, I've been asked a couple of times
我们是否有这门课程的阅读材料
whether we have reading materials for the course.
而且没有正式的阅读材料
And there are no formal reading materials,
但有几个资源我真的
but there are a couple of resources that I really
我喜欢阅读 尤其是在我对Lua和Love2D有了更多了解的时候
enjoyed reading, especially as I was getting more into Lua and Love2D.
这是两本书
They are two books.
一种是在线图书
One is an online book.
事实上 它们都是在线书籍 但后者
Actually, they're both online books, but the latter of which
也有一种物质形式
has a physical form as well.
第一个是丹·肖勒所著的如何制作RPG 它
The first of these is How to Make an RPG by Dan Schoeller, which
实际上完全是用Lua编写的
is actually completely written in Lua.
他使用的定制游戏引擎非常类似于Love2D
He uses a custom game engine very similar to Love2D,
但这是他亲笔写的
but it's handwritten by him.
但很多相同的想法都适用 这是一个很好的机会
But a lot of the same ideas apply, and it's a great opportunity.
这就是我对Lua咬牙的方式 我会
It's how I cut my teeth on Lua, and I would
如果你对此感兴趣 鼓励你去看一看
encourage you to take a look at that if that's something you're interested in,
或者如果你喜欢RPG的话
or if you like RPGs.
然后是Robert Nystrom的游戏编程模式
And then also Game Programming Patterns by Robert Nystrom
是一款非常棒的通用游戏开发
is a very great general purpose game development
这本书谈到了许多更抽象的高级概念
book that talks about a lot of the sort of more abstract high level concepts
伴随着大规模的游戏开发
with large scale game development.
但除此之外 没有正式的阅读
But beyond that, no formal reading.
这些也不是从阅读中获得的
Those aren't from reading either.
这些只是如果你好奇的话 你
Those are just if you're curious, and you
我想读一些我觉得很有趣的资源
want to read some resources that I found very interesting.
请随意这样做
Feel free to do so.
今天的目标是实现看起来像这样的东西
Today's goal is to implement what looks like this.
这是我们的飞鸟版本
This is our version of Flappy Bird.
出于版权目的 我们并没有使用完全相同的精灵
We didn't use the same exact sprites for copyright purposes,
但我们注意到 屏幕中央有一只鸟
but we note that we have a bird in the middle of the screen.
这只鸟 点击一下 或者在空格键上 会跳上跳下
This bird, on click, or on spacebar, will jump up and down,
你的目标是防止这只鸟碰到
and your goal is to prevent the bird from touching
要么是管道 要么是地面本身
either the pipes or the ground itself.
每次你通过一对管子 你就得一分
Every time you make it past a pair of pipes, you will score a point.
你一碰烟斗或落地 游戏就结束了
As soon as you touch a pipe or hit the ground, the game is over,
就是这样
and that's that.
所以今天我们将会报道--
So today we'll be covering--
我将进行更多的实时编码
I'll be doing a little bit more live coding.
所以我想要介绍的第一个例子
So the very first example that I want to cover
是Flappy Bird的零日更新
is the day zero update for Flappy Bird.
一个重要的功能可能是
And a important function that is going to be probably
最引人注目 最明显的功能 我们将
the most noticeable, the most visibly obvious function we'll
在整个演讲中使用的是love.graph ics.newImage
be using throughout this lecture, is love.graphics.newImage,
它走的是一条路
which takes a path.
这个功能 它所做的就是从你的磁盘上加载一个图像文件
This function, all it does is load a image file from your disk.
您将其指定为字符串 然后可以将其用作对象
You specify it as a string, and you can then use it as an object,
并在XY坐标下绘制任意位置
and draw anywhere you want at an xy coordinate,
我们将在这里的实践中看到这一点
and we'll see this in practice here.
所以我要继续了
So I'm going to go ahead.
如果你在回购中查看 所有这些例子都有涵盖--
If you're looking in the repo, all of these examples are covered--
0到12
0 through 12.
我将在我创建的新文件夹中从头开始
I'm going to start from scratch in a new folder that I've created.
我要创造一个全新的Main Lua 完全新鲜
I'm going to create a brand new main.lua, completely fresh.
我想做的第一件事是因为我们
And the first thing I want to do is because we
就像我们上周做的那样 使用虚拟分辨率
are going to use a virtual resolution just like we did last week,
为了让我们有更多的修辞 我要走了
so that we have a more rhetoric, I'm going
继续执行并需要推送库
to go ahead and require the push library.
因此 推动平等是必要的
So push equals require.
就像这样推
Push just like that.
我已将pres.lua预先放入此目录中
I've pre put push.lua into this directory.
默认情况下 它将加载到相同的目录中--
It'll just load by default in the same directory--
运行Love时脚本的当前工作目录
the current working directory of your script when you run Love.
接下来我要做的是 定义一些常量
The next thing I'm going to do, I'm going to define some constants.
所以窗宽应该是1280 然后窗高是720
So window with should be 1280, and then window height is going to be 720.
这些是我们的物理窗户尺寸
Those are our physical window dimensions,
但我们还需要一个虚拟宽度 我们将使用512乘以288
but then we also need a virtual width, and we're going to use 512 by 288.
我发现这一解决方案对我们的资产非常有效
This is a resolution that I found worked pretty well for the assets we'll
现在就用 但你可以把它做成任何你想要的东西
be using today, but you can make this most anything you want to as long
因为它在这个范围内的某个地方
as it's somewhere in that range.
它的分辨率也是16x9 所以很舒服
It is a 16 by 9 resolution as well, so that it fits comfortably
在现代宽屏16x9显示器上
on modern wide screen 16 by 9 monitors.
我们要做的是我们今天的第一个目标
What we're going to do is the first goal that we have today
就是在屏幕上绘制两个图像
is to draw two images to the screen.
我们想要前景和背景 因为注意到
We want a foreground and a background because notice,
如果我们回到幻灯片上 我们可以在背景中看到
if we go back to the slides, we can see in the very background
我们有一个山丘景观 然后在底部我们有一个地面
we have a hill landscape, and then on the bottom we have a ground.
这两家公司最终将以不同的速度滚动
The two of those are going to eventually scroll at different rates.
它将被称为视差滚动 但只是
It's going to be called parallax scrolling, but just
对于我们的第一个例子 我们想要一些非常基本的东西
for our very first example, we want something very basic.
我只想在屏幕上画两个图像
I just want to draw two images to the screen.
所以我们将在这里通过设置一个局部变量来实现这一点
So we're going to go ahead and do that here by setting a local variable.
记住 LOCAL意味着它只是被定义到
Remember, local means that it's just defined to the scope that
它是在 而不是全局的 这意味着我们不能访问这个变量
it's in, rather than being global, which means we cannot access this variable
在这份文件之外
outside of this file.
本地背景获取love.graph ics.newImage
Local background gets love.graphics.newImage,
我们刚才谈到的功能
the function that we just talked about.
让我继续把这个检查员藏在这里 这样我们就可以有更多的房间代码了
Let me go ahead and hide this inspector here so we can have more room code.
然后它只需要一根绳子
And then it's just going to take a string.
所以背景.png
So background.png.
我意识到我实际上并没有将这些文件包括在目录中
And I realize I actually didn't include those files in the directory.
所以我也需要这么做
So I'm going to need to do that as well.
地面也是一样 功能也完全一样
Same thing for the ground, exact same function,
Love.graph ics.newImage 除了round.png
love.graphics.newImage except ground.png.
趁我还没忘记 让我们现在就去做吧
And before I forget, let's go ahead, and do that right now.
我这里有文件
I have the files here.
所以背景和背景
So ground and background.
我们将把这些文件从发行版repo复制到我的Bird0目录中
We're going to copy those from the distro repo into my bird0 directory
我现在正在开发的
that I'm currently developing in right now.
一旦我们做完了 我们就会继续下去
And as soon as we're done with that, we're going to go ahead,
我们将定义love.Load 它
and we're going to define love.load, which
是在程序执行开始时调用的Love2D函数
is the function Love2D calls at the beginning of your program execution.
在那里 因为我们不想让这些图像看起来模糊
In there, because we don't want these images to look blurry
当他们被加载和升级时 我们希望
when they get loaded and upscaled, we want
要继续并在min和mag上将默认筛选器设置为最近
to go ahead and set our default filter to nearest on min and mag,
这意味着在高端和低端 应用最近邻居过滤 这
which means on upscale and downscale, apply nearest neighbor filtering, which
表示没有模糊 没有像素内插
means no blurriness, no interpolation of the pixels.
然后有一件事只是一个小小的触摸
And then one thing that is just a small little touch,
Love.window.settile五十只鸟因为它是GD50
love.window.setTitle fifty bird because it's GD50,
然后我们继续在这里设置我们的屏幕
and then we're going to go ahead and set up our screen here
用我们的虚拟宽度、虚拟高度、窗口宽度、窗口高度
with our virtual width, virtual height, window width, window height.
它变得有点长了 然后它就占据了桌子
It's getting a bit long, and then it takes in the table.
调用表格 只需像这样接受关键字
Recall tables, just take in keys like so.
与在Python中使用冒号不同 我们在Love中使用等号
Unlike in Python where you might use a colon, we use an equal sign in Love,
或者在卢阿岛 我应该说
or in Lua, I should say.
可调整为True 这就是我们的Load函数的末尾
Resizable to true, and that is the end of our load function.
现在 有没有人记得如果我们想要调整尺寸--
Now, does anybody recall how if we want to resize--
因此请注意 我将Resizable设置为True
so notice I set resizable to true.
我们知道如何发送消息来推动我们调整屏幕大小吗？
Do we know how we can send a message to push to resize our screen for us?
因此 Love2D定义了一个名为love.resize的函数
So Love2D to defines a function called love.resize,
它包含宽度和高度
which takes in a width and a height.
在那里 我们要做的就是推迟推动
And in there, all we're going to do is defer that call to push.
在推送时调用完全相同的函数
Recall the exact same function on push.
它需要一个宽度和高度 这将是
It takes a width and a height, and that will
注意动态调整其内部使用的画布的比例
take care of dynamically rescaling the canvas it uses internally.
它渲染到一个纹理 然后再渲染到这个纹理
It renders to a texture, and it's going to render to the texture
我们设置为虚拟宽度和虚拟高度
that we set as the virtual width and the virtual height,
它将对其进行缩放以适应我们的屏幕
and it's going to scale it to fit our screen.
它需要知道我们的物理屏幕尺寸
And it needs to know our physical screen dimensions
以便它实际上可以适当地适当地缩放内部画布
so that it can actually properly scale that internal canvas appropriately.
有人记得我们用来从用户那里获取输入的函数吗？
Does anybody remember the function that we use to get input from the user?
因此 函数.love.keyPressed recall 接受一个键
So function.love.keyPressed, recall, takes in a key.
每次我们按下一个键 爱就会自动呼唤
Love is going to call this automatically every time we press a key,
这将是--
and that's going to be--
我们将可以访问该密钥 我们可以进行任何类型的逻辑运算
and we're going to have access to that key, and we can do any sort of logic
我们想要那把钥匙 用那把钥匙
that we want on that key, using that key,
我们只需要给Love打个电话 退出
and we're just going to call love.event.quit
因为我不喜欢按命令Q或点击红色的x
because I don't like to press Command Q or click the red x.
我只想逃走 结束这一切
I just want to hit escape, be done with it.
然后我们的渲染是什么--Love的渲染函数叫什么？
And then what's our render-- what's Love's render function called?
这叫爱 画画
it's called love.draw.
所以给love.draw打电话吧
So call love.draw.
然后因为我们使用推送 有没有人
And then because we're using push, does anybody
请记住 我们需要实际执行哪些操作才能使推送渲染
remember what we need to actually do to get push to render
把我们的屏幕调到虚拟分辨率？
our screen to a virtual resolution?
回想一下 我们实际上有两种方法可以做到这一点
So recall that there's actually two ways we can do it.
我们可以调用Push Start和Push Finish 我们上周没有讨论这一点
We can call push start and push finish, which we didn't cover last week.
或者我们可以打电话--这实际上是一种新的事实上的方式
Or we can call-- and that's actually the new de facto way to do it.
或者我们可以使用PUSH APPLY START 这是不推荐使用的方法
Or we can do push apply start, which is the deprecated way to do it.
但从现在开始 我们将称之为Push Start
But starting from here on out, we're going to call push start
然后按下Finish
and push finish.
最后 我们有自己的图像
And then last, we have our images.
我们已经把它们作为物品分配到这里了
We've allocated them as objects up here.
我们有一个背景和一个背景
We have a background and a ground.
我们现在需要做的就是把它们吸引到屏幕上
All we need to do now is just draw them to the screen.
所以这是一个新函数
So this is a new function.
或者它实际上不是一个新功能
Or it's actually not a new function.
实际上 这是一个新功能
It is a new function, actually.
矩形是我们上周在所有绘制调用中使用的内容
Love.graphics.rectangle is what we used last week for all of the draw calls.
在本例中 我们希望绘制一个图像对象
In this case, we want to draw an image object,
我们在内存中拥有的纹理对象
a texture object that we have in memory.
所以我们将把它命名为love.graph ics.Drag
So we're going to call love.graphics.draw,
它需要一个可抽屉 这意味着
and it takes a drawable, which means anything
爱的定义是可以画出来的东西
that Love has defined as something that can be drawn.
在这种情况下 图像是可绘制的
In this case, images are drawables.
可以绘制它们 也可以在您指定的任何给定位置绘制它们
They can be drawn, and they can be drawn at any given position that you specify.
如果你想把它画在左上角
So if you wanted to draw it at the top left corner,
我们只会在0 0处说love.raphics.draBackground
we would just say love.graphics.drawBackground at 0,0,
而且它也有这种效果
and it has that effect.
我们要用我们的土地做同样的事情
And we're going to the exact same thing with our ground.
唯一的区别是 很明显 我们不会
The only difference being that obviously, we don't
想在角落的顶端画画
want to draw at the top of corner.
我们想在屏幕的底部画画
We want to draw at the bottom of the screen.
所以我们称之为虚拟身高减16 这是
So we just call virtual height minus 16, which
恰好是我们图像的高度
happens to be the height of our image.
所以如果你运行这个--
So if you run this--
我将继续 并确保我在正确的目录中
I'm going to go ahead, and make sure I'm in the right directory.
我不在正确的目录中 所以我将进入我编写的目录
I'm not in the right directory, so I'm going to go into a directory I wrote,
五十只鸟抓伤
fifty bird scratch.
进入小鸟0号
Go into bird0.
如果我运行这个 理论上我应该只有两个图像
And if I run this, I should theoretically have just two images
层叠在一起 但我不会
layered on top of each other, which I do not.
所以我们只需要确保它被保存下来
So we just make sure that it gets saved.
记住要始终保存您的工作 这样就可以了
Remember to always save your work, and there you go.
所以我们现在所做的 看起来比上周好多了
So all we're doing now, it looks infinitely better than last week
已经有了 但它非常简单 只有很少的代码行
already, but it's very simple, very few lines of code.
我们为此付出的所有努力
All the effort that we've put into it has
一直是我们精灵编辑的首选 而你
been in our sprite editor of choice, and you
几乎可以使用任何你想做这类事情的应用程序
can use most any application you want to do this sort of stuff.
我用一个叫Aseprite的程序 我很喜欢
I use a program called Aseprite, I like a lot,
但你可以用免费的Gimp做这件事 你可以用Photoshop做这件事
but you could do this in Gimp, which is free, you could do it in Photoshop,
如果你愿意 你可以用微软的画笔来完成
you could do it in Microsoft Paint if you wanted to.
如果你这么做的话祝你好运
Godspeed if you do.
但是 是的 这就像把图像画到屏幕上一样简单
But yeah, so that's as simple as it is just to draw images to the screen.
所以我们已经在很短的时间内取得了相当大的进展
So we've already made quite a lot of progress in a very short period of time
在我们游戏的视觉方面
in terms of the visual aspect of our game.
但是 除了最初的那种蜜月之外 看起来并不有趣
But it's not interesting to look at beyond the initial sort of honeymoon
到目前为止 我们在屏幕上有了颜色
period of now we have colors on the screen.
我们想要真正开始滚动 因为这个游戏 Recall 是
We want to actually get scrolling because the game, recall, is
滚动游戏
a scrolling game.
实际上 有谁愿意自愿
And actually, would anybody be willing to volunteer
上台演奏《飞翔的小鸟》 这样我们就可以在舞台上看到现场表演了？
to come up, and play Flappy Bird just so we can see it live on the stage?
大卫 你想上来玩吗？
David, you want to come up and play?
有志愿者吗？
Does someone volunteer?
史蒂芬 你想上来玩吗？
Stephen, you want to come up and play?
史蒂芬：当然可以
STEPHEN: Sure.
科尔顿·奥格登：谢谢你的志愿服务
COLTON OGDEN: Thank you for volunteering.
我保证你比我更擅长这个游戏
I guarantee you're better at this game than I am.
我将继续并cd进入目录中的Bird12 即
I'm going to go ahead and cd into bird12 in the directory, which is
游戏的最终版本完成
the final version of the game complete.
所以我要继续按Enter键
So I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
[电子游戏音乐播放]
[VIDEO GAME MUSIC PLAYING]
因此 我们已经可以看到视差滚动
So already, we can see the parallax scrolling
我之前提到的 就是楼层
that I referred to before, which is the floor
背景以不同的速度滚动
and the background are scrolling at different rates,
我们很快就会在下一个例子中看到这一点
and we'll see this very shortly in the next example.
我们有一个提示符
We have a prompt.
我们收到短信了
We have text.
我们以前已经在字体中使用过这一点
We've already used this before with the font.
所以继续 如果你按Enter 你就会倒计时
So go ahead, if you press Enter, you're going to get a count down.
所以太空就是跳跃
So space is to jump.
[嘟嘟声]
[BEEPING]
所以我们让我们的鸟在屏幕中央跳跃
So we have our bird jumping in the middle of the screen.
我们得了第一名的分数
We have a score at the top.
这样做的目的是避免撞到管道
The goal is to avoid hitting the pipes.
[撞车]
[CRASH]
好的 得一分
OK, a score of one.
你想再试一次吗？
You want to try again?
您先请
Go ahead.
[嘟嘟声]
[BEEPING]
所以它会记录他的位置 每次
So it keeps track of his position, and every time
他穿过了一对管子的右边 如你所见
he gets past the right edge of a pair of pipes, as you can see,
这就是他得到一分的时候
that's when he gets a point.
那么如果你回想起上周 我们认为是什么--
So if you recall from last week, what do we think is--
是什么在检测碰撞？
what's detecting the collision?
如果我们记得上个星期 这个词叫什么？
If we remember last week, what's the term?
有人记得吗？
Anybody remember?
轴对齐边界AABB碰撞检测 轴对齐边界框
Axis aligned bound aabb collision detection, axis-aligned bounding box.
这和我们对Pong做的事情是一样的 只是现在我们正在做--
It's the same thing that we did with Pong, except now we're doing it--
我们有图形 但它的概念是一样的
we have graphics, but it's the same exact concept.
我们只是使用矩形
We're just using rectangles.
当一个矩形与另一个矩形重叠时 我们就会触发死亡
And when one rectangle overlaps with another rectangle, we trigger death.
所以我想是最后一次迭代 然后我们将
So one last iteration I think, and then we'll.
[撞车]
[CRASH]
我们会让你再试一次
We'll let you try one more time.
您先请
Go ahead.
我会试一试
I'll give it a shot.
我要故意输掉比赛
I'm going to lose on purpose.
好了 我们开始吧
OK, here we go.
说句公道话 我在开发这个的时候有过很多练习
To be unfair, I got plenty of practice when I was developing this,
但我们将拭目以待 看看这是否真的适用于这里
but we'll see if that actually holds true here.
所以还要注意 这些管子--
So notice also, the pipes--
我--哦 我失去了程序世代
the procedure generation that I-- oh, I lost.
三分
Three points.
当我再做一次迭代时 让我再解释一下
Let me explain a little bit more, while I do one more iteration.
但是管子本身 每次我们开始的时候
But the pipes themselves, every time we start,
它们在不同的地点产卵
they're spawning at a different location.
这几乎是在最简单的情况下进行的
This is proceeded generation in pretty much the most simplest
可能的方法 并注意到管道正在逐渐移动
way possible, and notice that the pipes are shifting gradually.
所以这在某种程度上是我们水平的构成
So this is sort of the make up of our level,
它只是对一些简单的算法一点一点地生成DO
and it's just generating bit by bit do to some simple algorithm
我们只会说 嘿 在这里再生产一根烟斗 把它移开
that we have that just says hey, spawn another pipe here, shift it
在一定程度上
by some amount.
这种非常简单的方法允许我们一遍又一遍地拥有无限的水平
And this very simple approach allows us to have an infinite level over and over
再说一次 这是非常有效的
again, and it's very efficient.
我们的屏幕上只有那么多的管子 我们很快就会看到--
We only ever have as many pipes on the screen, and as we'll see soon--
内存中的管道数量只能与屏幕上看到的一样多
we'll only have as many pipes in memory as we can see on the screen
有一段时间 尽管这一水平理论上可以
at one time, despite the fact that this level could theoretically
无限地进行 所以这是非常划算的
go on infinitely, and so it's very cost efficient.
因此 Bird1就是一个例子
So bird1 is the example.
这是视差更新
It's the parallax update.
因此 视差滚动是2D中的一个重要概念
So parallax scrolling is an important concept in 2D
还有3D 但2D游戏开发
and also 3D, but 2D game development.
它指的是在两个参照系的情况下运动的错觉
It refers to the illusion of movement given two frames of reference
以不同的速度移动
that are moving at different rates.
所以如果你在高速公路上开车 你看到你旁边有一道栅栏
So if you're driving on the highway, and you see a fence next to you,
你看到远处的群山 你就是
and you see mountains in the distance, you're
通过观察栅栏移动的速度来观察视差滚动
observing parallax scroll by seeing how fast the fence moves
相对于山脉而言
relative to the mountains.
山脉的移动速度会比栅栏慢得多
The mountains are going to move a lot more slowly than the fences right
就在你旁边
next to you.
我们在我们的游戏中完成了同样的幻觉
And we accomplish the same exact illusion in our game
通过使用这种图形错觉
by using this sort of graphical illusion.
所以我将在我的目录中继续
And so I'm going to go ahead in my directory
在这里 在鸟1号 这是一种无人居住的--
here, in bird1, which is an unpopulated--
它填充了Bird0的内容 即Bird0的完整内容
it's populated with the contents of bird0, the complete contents of bird0.
您将看到的版本将包含所有代码
The version that you'll see will have all of the code,
但我将继续 如果我们在该目录中运行Bird0
but I'm going to go ahead, and if we run bird0 in that directory.
所以我想现在我还在完整的发行版中
So I think right now I'm still in the full distro.
所以让我继续 再一次进入五十鸟抓
So let me go ahead, go into fifty bird scratch again.
哎呀 我在哪里？
Whoops, where am I?
然后我将进入Bird1 并运行它
And then I'm going to go into bird1, and run it,
我得到了和上次一模一样的图像
and I get the exact same image that we had last time.
所以一切都是从以前开始的 只有两张图片 没有任何移动
So everything is there from before, just two images, nothing moving,
我们观察不到视差
no parallax that we can observe.
我将继续进行 并开始实施
I'm going to go ahead, and start implementing
这种视差的基本原理
the basics of this parallax.
所以如果我继续我的主修课程
So if I go ahead in my main.
因此 我将在这里介绍一下我们的背景
So I'm going to go down here to where we have our background.
所以我们需要一些新的东西
So we need a couple of new things.
因此 与我们的背景图像一起 我们需要
So along with our background image, we need
来跟踪它的滚动量 因为我们
to keep track of how much it's scrolled because we're
需要开始将此图像绘制到屏幕上
going to need to start drawing this image to the screen,
但如果我们要滚动它 那就意味着
but if we're going to scroll it, that means
我们需要移动它的x偏移量
that we need to shift its x offset.
如果我们想让它滚动 而不是在0 0处绘制
Instead of drawing it at 0,0, if we want it to scroll,
相反 我们不得不把它画在某个负值上
we have to draw it at some negative value instead.
随着时间的推移 这将产生它从右向左移动的效果
Over time, this will have the effect of it moving right to left.
所以我要继续下去 并跟踪--
So I'm going to go ahead, and keep track--
我将使用一个变量来跟踪卷轴
I'm going to use a variable to keep track of the scroll
现在 对于这两张图片 我们只是
now, for both of these images, and we're just
我要将它们命名为BackdowScroll和Ground Scroll 并将它们设置为0
going to call them backgroundScroll and groundScroll, and set them to 0.
所以这会产生NOX偏移量的影响
So this is going to have the effect of no x offset.
所以我现在可以使用这个变量 在下面的这个绘图调用中
So I could use this variable right now in this draw call down here,
我真的要这么做
which I'm actually going to do.
我要继续下去 去--
I'm going to go ahead, and go to--
我要去看看那是不是对的
I'm just going to find out if that is correct.
我将继续将其设置为负背景滚动
I'm going to go ahead and set that to negative backgroundScroll.
在这里 我将把它设置为负值
And here, I'm going to set this to negative groundScroll.
因此 这还不会改变任何事情
So this is not going to change anything yet.
这将是完全相同的事情 因为它们都是0
It's going to be the exact same thing because they're both 0.
它们以前是0 但随着时间的推移 我们会改变它们
They were 0 before, but we're going to change them over time.
为了做到这一点 我将继续下去 进入到这里
And in order to do this, I'm going to go ahead, and go into up here.
实际上 在我们做这件事之前 我们需要设定一个速度
One thing before we do that actually, we need to set a speed for this.
这将随着时间的推移而发生 但由于他们
This is going to happen over time, but since they
需要以不同的速度发生 背景
need to occur at different rates, the background
需要以比前景更慢的速度运行
needs to go at a slower rate than the foreground
为了得到视差效应 我们需要分离速度变量
so that we do get this parallax effect, we need to separate speed variables.
一般来说 不会改变的东西的标准是
Generally, the norm for something that is not going to change
就是用大写字母加下划线
is to write it in caps with underscores.
这是常量记法
This is constant notation.
这在大多数编程语言中都很常见
This is frequently seen in most programming languages.
我们将在这里使用它
We'll use it here.
我将设置一个名为BACKGROUND_SCROLL_SPEED的变量
I'm going to set a variable called BACKGROUND_SCROLL_SPEED,
我要把它设为30
and I'm just going to set that to 30.
我也要做同样的事情 GROUND_SCROLL_SPEED
I'm going to do the same thing, GROUND_SCROLL_SPEED.
这是否需要高于或低于BACKGROUND_SCROLL_SPEED？
Does this need to be higher or lower than the BACKGROUND_SCROLL_SPEED?
地面将会移动--
The ground is going to move--
因此 背景的移动速度需要比地面慢
so the background needs to move slower than the ground does.
所以这个数字会更高
So this is going to be higher.
所以我们只需将其设置为60
So we're just going to set it to 60.
您可以将其设置为任何您想要获得的效果
You can set it to whatever you want to get the effect that you want,
但这一点已经相当明显了
but this will already be quite noticeable.
地面的移动速度将是背景的两倍
The ground is going to move twice as fast as the background.
所以我们要做的也是如果我们
And so what we're going to do also is if we
如果我们让我们的图像无限滚动 会发生什么呢？
just-- so what's going to happen if we just let our image scroll infinitely?
在某个时间点上会发生什么？
What's going to happen at a certain point?
观众：形象消失了？
AUDIENCE: Run out of image?
科尔顿·奥格登：它将以一种形象运行
COLTON OGDEN: It's going run at an image.
那么 我们如何解决这个问题呢？
So how do we fix this problem?
观众：循环播放
AUDIENCE: Loop it.
科尔顿·奥格登：准确地说 是循环
COLTON OGDEN: Loop it, exactly.
所以我们要继续下去 设置一个循环点
So we're going to go ahead, and set a looping point.
因此 另一个恒定的背景循环点
So another constant background looping point,
我们要将其设置为413 这有点像
and we're going to set this to 413, which you kind of have
为了查看你的图像 并确定--你必须设置你的图像
to look at your image, and determine-- you sort of have to set your images up,
如果你想达到这个效果 就让它们成为一个循环的图像
if you want to achieve this effect, by having them be a looping image.
所以有两个拷贝完全相同的东西 也就是你的屏幕宽度
So have either two copies of the exact same thing that's your screen width,
或者只是复制相同的块 一遍又一遍
or just copy the same chunk over, and over again.
有很多方法可以做到这一点
There's many ways to do it.
在本例中 我们的背景图像的循环点
In this case, the looping point of the image of our background
在x轴上是413
is 413 on the x-axis.
所以我们把它设为413
So we're going to set that to 413.
然后我们继续--下一步我们实际上有
And then we're going to go ahead-- the next step is we actually have
开始改变价值观
to start changing the value values.
所以在我们的更新函数中
So in our update function, which is where
这是会发生的 我会继续
this is going to happen, I'm going to go ahead,
爱的定义 更新 回忆起来 Love 2D将为你打电话
and define love.update, which recall, Love2D will call for you,
但你必须自己定义
but you must define it yourself.
我要继续 并设置backgroundScroll
I'm going to go ahead, and set backgroundScroll too.
所以这是要做什么 背景滚动
So what this is going to do, backgroundScroll
获取backgroundScroll到自身加上我们设置的速度before times delta time
gets backgroundScroll to itself plus the speed we set before times delta time.
所以它保持帧速率独立
So it stays frame rate independent.
这会给我们的图像增加速度
That will have the effect of adding the speed to our image,
但我们得重新设置
but we need to reset it.
我们需要真正执行重置
We need to actually perform the reset.
为了做到这一点 我们只需要使用模
And to do that, we'll just be using Modulus, which recall
从像C这样的语言 简单地划分--
from languages like C, simply divides--
基本上 将该值设置为该除法的余数
basically, sets that value to the remainder of that division.
在这种情况下10模5等于0
So in this case-- so 10 modulo 5 would be 0,
但10模9实际上等于1 因为我们有0
but 10 modulo 9 would be 1, effectively, because we have 0
剩下的部分
left over once we divide 10 by 5.
我们用10除以9就剩下1
We have 1 left over once we divide 10 by 9.
所以我很抱歉 如果这个概念不是新的
So I apologize if that concept is not new.
但我们也要为我们的土地做同样的事情
But we're going to do the same exact thing for our ground,
只不过我们要对虚拟宽度取模
only we're going to modulo by our virtual width in this case.
我没有设置循环点
I did not set a looping point.
在后面的例子中是这样的 但是我们的地面图像非常--
I do in later examples, but our ground image is very--
它的一致性足以让你
it's consistent enough such that you don't even
注意它在循环时没有使用虚拟with
notice it when it loops without just using the virtual with.
所以在这种情况下 我们只使用虚拟宽度
So we're just going to use the virtual width in that case.
它很有图案 而且很小
It's very patterned, and very small.
除此之外 我们已经有了背景卷轴
And aside from that, we already have the background scrolls here
在我们的绘图功能中
in our draw functions.
所以当我们运行这段代码时 理论上我们应该
So when we run this code, we should theoretically
有滚动的背景
have scrolling background.
观众：那么它的宽度是不是要两倍呢
AUDIENCE: So does it even just have to be twice the width
这样就不会卖完了
or something so they don't run out?
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 至少是宽度的两倍
COLTON OGDEN: They do, at least twice the width, yes.
有几种方法可以有效地平铺你的形象
There's ways you could effectively tile your image,
这样做可以节省纹理大小的内存
and do it that way to save memory on texture size.
如果你有屏幕大小的四分之一的东西
If you have maybe something that's a quarter of the screen size
你想要循环 一遍又一遍 你
that you want to loop over, and over again, you
我不想把它当做一个大画面
don't want to have that as one big image,
您只需绘制该图像的四个副本来填充您的屏幕
you'll just draw four copies of that image to fill your screen,
然后把它们全部移走
and then to shift all of them.
可能有五个 实际上 所以你有一点
Maybe five, actually, so you have a little bit
超出屏幕边缘 然后将它们全部放回0
beyond the edge of the screen, and then just put all of them back to 0.
观众：所以最下面的那个 地面是--
AUDIENCE: So the bottom one, the ground is--
如果您只是重新开始显示带有较大图像的图像 您不会知道
you wouldn't know if you just restarted showing the image with the larger
背景资料
background.
你就不用担心山被切成两半了
You wouldn't have to worry about the mountain getting cut in half
当你换掉右翼时--
when you replaced the right--
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
所以我们实际上可以--
So we could actually--
我现在就可以向你展示那会是什么样子
I could show you right now what that will look like.
所以如果我们把这里的循环点去掉
So if we just take out the looping point here,
或者我们将其设置为完全不准确的值 比如270
or we set it to some value that's completely inaccurate like 270,
然后我们运行它 一段时间后它应该会停下来
and then we run it, after a while it should just cut.
是的 就在那里
Yeah, right there.
观众：那么你真的要画两次吗？
AUDIENCE: So are you drawing it twice, really?
就像用完的时候一个接一个什么的？
Like one after another one when it runs out or something?
科尔顿·奥格登：不 图像太宽了 总是会填满屏幕
COLTON OGDEN: No, the image is so wide that it always will fill the screen,
即使在它被设置回--即使在它超过了循环点之后
even after it's been set back to-- even after it's gone past the looping point.
我忘了纹理有多大了
I forget how large the texture is.
它有1157个像素宽
It is 1157 pixels wide.
所以它是屏幕宽度的两倍多
So it's more than twice the screen width.
实际上 我认为它正好是屏幕宽度的两倍
Actually, I think it is exactly twice the screen width.
不 它不是屏幕宽度的两倍
No, it's not exactly twice the screen width,
但它是屏幕宽度的两倍多
but it's more than twice the screen width
所以当413个像素已经过去的时候
so that when the amount-- the 413 pixels has elapsed,
它仍然远远超过了屏幕的右边缘和循环部分
it's still plenty past the right edge of the screen, and the looping part,
它将与纹理上的外观完全相同
it'll be the exact same appearance on the texture,
但它完全被移回了右翼
but it's completely been shifted back to the right.
我们图像的0 0现在位于屏幕空间中的0 0
The 0,0 of our image is now at 0,0 in our screen space.
观众：所以循环只是重新加载[INAUDIBLE]？？
AUDIENCE: So the looping is just reloading [INAUDIBLE]??
科尔顿·奥格登：你的形象在这里 在移动 然后就在瞬间
COLTON OGDEN: Your image is here, moving, and then just instantly
回到开始 然后回到--
back to the beginning, and then moving back to--
将其设置回0 或者从技术上讲 多少
the setting it back to 0 or technically, how many
像素它已经超过了屏幕的边缘 因为使用了模数
pixels it's gone past the edge of the screen because using modulo.
观众：所以这只是一张图片
AUDIENCE: So it's just one image.
这就像你只需在正确的时间瞬间翻转它
It's like you just instantaneously flip it at the right time.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
这是一种翻译
It's a translation.
这是一种即时翻译
It's an instant translation.
它发生在一帧上
It takes place over one frame.
所以你没有注意到它
So you don't notice it.
你的肉眼看不到它 因为它实际上发生在一帧中
Your human eye can't see it because it literally happens in one frame.
这两个点的图像数据是完全相同的
The image data is the exact same at those two points
因为我们有质感
because we have a texture.
我们已经预先创建了一个具有完全相同数据的纹理
We've pre-created a texture that has the exact same data
这样你就有了这样的效果
so that you have that effect.
你必须有一个纹理 让你能做到这一点 或者聪明
You have to have a texture that allows you to do this, or smartly
画出四幅相同的图像
draw four of the same images.
跟踪他们所有四个人--
Keep track of all four of them--
或者实际上 有八个--所以你可以把它们移到左边
or actually, eight of them-- so you can move them to the left,
然后把它们全部移回右边
and then shift them all back to the right.
观众：我想我们拍《超级马里奥兄弟》的时候
AUDIENCE: I assume when we do Super Mario Bros.,
我们将有多个图像一个接一个地堆叠在一起
we're going to have multiple images that get stacked one after another.
科尔顿·奥格登：当我们谈到超级马里奥兄弟时
COLTON OGDEN: When we get to Super Mario Bros.,
我们将讨论一个称为平铺映射的概念 它
we'll be talking about a concept called tile mapping, which
就是我们拿一个雪碧纸 然后你基本上把它切碎
is where we take a sprite sheet, and then you basically chop it up
有一张地图 基本上是数字的 所以一块砖是
into pieces, have a map that is basically numerical so that a brick is
值为1 然后你可以看到这个巨大的二维数组
value one, and then you look through this giant two dimensional array
然后遍历它 迭代它
that you have, and then go over it, iterate over it,
然后根据地图上的索引在一定的偏移量上绘制一块瓷砖
and then draw a tile at an offset based on your index into that map.
所以它稍微复杂一点 而且实际上内存要大得多
So it's a little bit more complicated, and actually a lot more memory
高效 但实现略有不同
efficient, but slightly different implementation.
好的 现在我们有视差滚动了
OK, so we have parallax scrolling now.
我想花点时间--
I want to take a moment to--
因为我们已经谈到了--
because we've touched on--
这是一种非常入门的方式来证明游戏是错觉
this is a very introductory way of demonstrating that games are illusions,
通过使用视差滚动
by using parallax scrolling.
实际上 我们所做的只是设置了两种不同的滚动速度
All we've done, really, is just set two things to scroll at different rates,
这让我们觉得我们在场景中有深度
and this has made us feel like we have depth in our scene,
但我们所做的一切 我们有两个图像 我们是
but all we're doing, we have two images, we're
以不同的速度滚动它们
scrolling them at different rates.
但这是游戏开发中的一个共同主题
But this is a common theme in game development,
正在试图设计一个可能非常精致的场景
is trying to devise a scene that maybe is very elaborate,
但在像iPhone这样的资源密集型设备上做到这一点
but doing it on very resource intensive devices like your iPhone,
或者像任天堂64这样的老式游戏机
or like an old console like the Nintendo 64.
这些错觉随处可见 一个YouTube频道
These illusions are all over the place, and a YouTube channel
我最近发现我真正喜欢的是
that I recently found that I really like is
这叫--频道的名字是她说的 但实际上他们的节目
it's called-- the name of the channel is She Says, but the actual show that they
HAVE被称为边界突破
have is called Boundary Break.
他们所做的就是拿起一台摄像机
And what they do is they take a camera that
超越了游戏开发商允许它做的事情
goes beyond what the game developers allowed it to do,
他们基本上侵入了游戏摄像头 这样你就可以在
which they basically hack the game camera so you can see in places where
你以前不应该看到的 而你
you weren't supposed to see before, and you
可以看到很多非常酷的诡计
can see a lot of really cool trickery.
我要给你们看几个视频片段
I'm about to show you a couple of video clips,
不过 如果你对视频感兴趣的话 这里有YouTube的网址
but here's the YouTube URL if you're curious to see the exact video.
这是一个大约33分钟的视频
It's about a 33 minute video.
这是在塞尔达 奥卡里纳的时间为N64
It's on Zelda, Ocarina of Time for the N64.
我提取了几个特别值得注意的片段
And I extracted a couple of particularly noteworthy clips
我觉得很有趣 也很幽默
that I thought were kind of interesting, and also humorous.
我现在要继续播放这段视频
I'm going to go ahead and show the clip now.
所以如果我们可以把灯光调暗 我就开始了
So if we could dim the lights, I'll go ahead and start.
这是第一个例子
This is the first example.
演讲者1：好的 关于这家商店有很多可谈的
SPEAKER 1: OK, so there's a lot to talk about with the shop
《时代的奥卡里纳》中的主人
owners in the Ocarina of Time.
所以我要把它浓缩成最有趣的
So I'm going to just condense it down to the most interesting,
我们要谈论的第一个问题是
and the first one we're going to talk about
是海鲁尔的那个怪异的店主
is the bizarre shop owner in Hyrule.
现在 在马约拉的面具中 同样的角色实际上是有腿的
Now, in Majora's Mask, the very same character is actually shown with legs,
但在《时代的奥卡莉娜》中 他没有这些
but in Ocarina of Time, he did not have those.
事实上 他没有腿看起来非常滑稽
In fact, he looks extremely hilarious without his legs.
科尔顿·奥格登：所以这是一个--
COLTON OGDEN: So this is a--
有没有人知道他们为什么要这么做？
does anybody have an instinct as to why they might have done this this way?
观众：反正你不会看到的
AUDIENCE: You're not going to see it anyway.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错 除此之外 还节省了内存
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly, and beyond that, also just saving on memory.
无需加载角色模型--相关的顶点和纹理
Not having to load a character model-- the vertices and textures associated
用它--
with it--
像N64这样内存受限的设备
on such a memory constrained device like the N64.
我忘了它有多少内存
I forget how much memory it had.
比如4兆字节的内存 我想还不到
Like four megabytes of memory, I think less than that.
因此 他们显然正在削减他们可以削减多少角落
And so they are obviously cutting however many corners they could.
在这种情况下 通过字面上使用的错觉
In this case, by literally using the illusion
不是幻觉 而是你只能看到
of looking-- not the illusion, but just the fact that you only could see over
柜台 给你一个错觉 有一个完整的生活
the counter, and giving you the illusion that there's a fully living,
会说话的店主但它只是半个模型
talking shop keeper there, but it's just half a model.
这里的另一个例子更多的是展示时间陶笛
And other example here is more to show how Ocarina of Time
利用N64有限的内存
used the N64's limited memory to give you
一种感觉 在一个非常大的水平 而你可能实际上并没有
the sense of being in a very large level when you might not actually have been.
所以如果我们能把灯光调暗一次 我们将继续展示这个
So if we could dim the lights one time, we'll go ahead and show this.
演讲者1：这显然是一个热门的建议
SPEAKER 1: So this one was apparently a hot suggestion,
[笑]
[CHUCKLES]
这是死亡山的免费摄像机 包括我们的朋友 大戈兰
which is free camera on Death Mountain, including our friend, Big Goran.
在黑色天空的映衬下 烟圈看起来有点奇怪
The smoke halo looks sort of weird against the black sky,
这里你可以看到任天堂愚弄了我们
and here you can see Nintendo fooled us.
它不是整座山 只有悬崖的表面被渲染
It's not full mountain, only the cliff face is actually rendered,
那是通往烈火圣殿的路
and that's the path leading towards the Fire Temple.
如果我们缩小 我们可以看到整个拖把的规模
And if we zoom out, we can see the scale of the whole mop.
比我想象的要大
Bigger than I thought it would be actually.
不过 战斗音乐不太适合史诗般的平移镜头
The battle music's not quite fitting for an epic panning shot, though.
科尔顿·奥格登：同样的想法 真的 只是有限的内存空间
COLTON OGDEN: Same idea here, really, just limited memory space.
所以让我们尽可能多地了解你
So let's load you know as much as we could possibly ever
从林克摄影机的角度来看
see from the perspective of the camera of Link,
我想这其实和人们
and it's actually very similar to how, I guess, people
在现实生活中创造一些场景让你觉得你是在一个
create stages in real life to make you feel as if you're in a--
当你去看戏的时候 感觉你真的在一个场景里
when you go to a play, feel like you're actually in a scene.
但他们显然已经尽可能多的削减角落 但它的工作
But they've clearly cut as many corners as possible, but it works.
在游戏中 你无法分辨 这在游戏开发中很常见
In the game, you can't tell, and that's very common in game development.
如果你想达到一个特别宏伟的效果
If you're trying to achieve a particularly grand effect,
这是一个需要思考的问题
it's something to think about is how can I
让我看起来像是在做什么但实际上我没有
make it seem like I'm doing something, but I'm actually not.
我怎样才能让它看起来像我是一只鸟飞过一个无限系列
How can I make it seem like I'm a bird flying through an infinite series
但实际上我不是
of levels, but I'm actually not.
我们还有更多精彩节目即将播出
We have a lot of more of that to show coming up soon.
到目前为止 我们有我们的背景 但我们没有
So far we have our background, but we don't
有我们游戏的标题人物 在这种情况下 五十鸟
have the title character of our game, and in this case, fifty bird.
所以我将继续 并说明我们如何得到一只鸟
So I'm going to go ahead, and illustrate how we can get a bird actually
渲染在屏幕上
rendering on the screen.
所以我将进入我创建的bird 2目录
So I'm going to go ahead into my bird2 directory here, that I've created.
再次注意 如果你已经加载了代码
And note again, bird2 in your directory if you've loaded the code,
将会有完整的实施
is going to have the complete implementation.
但总的来说 我会做几件事
But in main, I'm going to do a couple of things.
实际上 我要做的第一件事
So actually, the first thing I'm going to do,
我们要注意到我已经包括了
we're going to-- notice that I've included--
实际上 我没有包括类文件
actually, I haven't included the class file.
所以我现在就去做
So I'm going to do that right now.
所以在bird 1中--对不起 我将从bird 3中获取类lua
So in bird1-- sorry, I'm going to take from bird3, the class.lua.
我将把它输入bird 2 因为我们
I'm going to go ahead, and put it into bird2 because we're
我们要做一个鸟类课
going to make a bird class.
回想一下 从上周开始
Recall, from last week, a class is just a way
把我们曾经认为是完全不同的变量
of taking several variables that we might once have had disparate from one
另一个是把它们放在一个包里
another, putting them together in a package,
把与这些变量相关的函数
putting functions associated with those variables
这样我们就能打电话
together so that we can call--
我们可以把游戏世界想得更抽象
we can sort of think of our game world more abstractly, and more
分隔开的 更干净的
compartmentalized, and cleaner.
所以我要继续--现在我有bird 2 类lua
So I'm going to go ahead-- and now I have in bird2, the class.lua.
这只是我们在Lua中使用Love 2D获取类的库
That's just the library we're using to get classes in Love2D in Lua.
我要继续 我要创建一个新文件
I'm going to go ahead, and I'm going to create a new file.
这只叫Bird.Lua
This one's called bird.lua.
所以请记住 趋势是类 将它们大写以区分它们
So remember, the trend is for classes, capitalize them to differentiate them
从函数和变量
from functions and variables.
这一次 我将继续 只需继续使用我的小抄
This one I'm going to go ahead, and just go ahead and use my cheat sheet here.
我的床单粘在一起了
My sheets are sticking together.
好的 这个鸟类课实际上相当简单
OK, so this bird class is actually fairly simple.
回想一下 我们要做的就是创建一个类
Recall that all we have to do to create a class
就是使用类库 大写的C加上括号
is just use the class library, the capital C with the brackets
在那里初始化它
there to initialize it.
我们将继续定义我们的init函数
We're going to go ahead and define our init function.
因此 每个类都有一个初始化对象的init函数
So every class has an init function, which initializes the object
它将在后面提到
that it's going to refer to later.
在这种情况下 我们需要一些东西
In this case, we're going to need a few things.
所以我们需要一张这只鸟的照片
So we're going to need an image for our bird
因为我们希望它能被吸引到屏幕上
because we want it to draw to the screen,
所以我们需要做的 和我们之前做的一样--
and so what we need to do, same thing that we did before--
Love.graph ics.newImage
love.graphics.newImage.
我要继续下去 很快地把它藏起来
I'm going to go ahead, and hide this really fast.
然后是Bird.png
And then bird.png.
简单 简单
Simple, easy.
我们想要我们的鸟的高度的宽度
We want the width in the height of our bird.
所以我要继续 把它也设置好
So I'm going to go ahead, and set that too.
因此 每个图像都有一组关联的函数
So every image has a set of functions associated
有了它 爱为我们实现了
with it that Love implements for us.
我们从love.graph ics.newImage上得到的图像
The image that we get back from love.graphics.newImage
本身就是一个类 它有一个名为getWidth的函数
is itself, sort of a class, which has a function called getwidth.
因此 这将允许我们动态地实现任何
So this will allow us to achieve the with, dynamically, of whatever
班级我们--
class we--
我们碰巧分配的任何图像文件 并从中创建对象
whatever image file we happen to allocate, and create an object from.
然后我们继续设置x和y 因为回想一下
And then we're going to go ahead and set our x and y because recall,
我们必须把它画在某个地方
we have to draw it somewhere.
我们想把我们的鸟画在屏幕中央
We want to draw our bird in the middle of the screen.
所以我们要继续 计算一下这个
So we're going to go ahead, and just calculate this
根据我们的虚拟宽度
based on our virtual width.
所以我们要做的是用虚拟宽度除以2
So we're going to do VIRTUAL_WIDTH divided by 2.
所以它在屏幕的中间
So it's halfway in the middle of the screen,
但由于它是从左上角画出来的
but since it draws from the top left corner,
我们想把它移到左边
we want to shift it to the left.
所以我们要用我们的宽度--
So we're going to use our width that we just--
即时错误--我们刚刚根据图像数据进行了初始化
instant error-- we just initialized from the image data,
然后我们要做的是自宽除以2
and then we're going to do a self.width divided by 2.
所以我们要把宽度除以2 在x轴上向左移动
So we're going to divide the width by 2, shift that to the left on our x-axis.
这将把我们放在水平方向的中间
That's going to put us in the middle, horizontally.
在垂直方向上 它是完全相同的 只是重复使用了高度而不是宽度
Vertically, it's the exact same thing, except reusing height instead of width.
差不多就是这样 除了这里的最后一点
And that's pretty much it, except for one the last bit here.
我们希望能够让我们的鸟变得非常重要
We want to be able to render our bird, pretty important.
所以我们要做love.graph 绘制我们的图像 然后在self.x self.y
So we're going to do love.graphics.draw our image, and then at self.x, self.y.
所以这就是我们真正需要的
And so this is all we really need just to get
一个非常简单的精灵出现在屏幕上
a very simple sprite onto the screen.
现在 它什么也做不了 因为这种人生活在
Now, it's not going to do anything because this sort of lives
目前还处于真空状态
in a vacuum at the moment.
我们需要做的是在我们的主文件中 我们
What we need to do is in our main file, we're
这将需要鸟 这实际上将把它放入我们的--
going to require bird, which is going to actually put it into our--
允许我们在代码中使用它
allow us to use it in our code.
我们将创建一个本地鸟类变量
We're going to create a local bird variable.
我们就叫它小鸟吧
We're just going to call it bird.
在那之后 我们将简单地渲染到屏幕上
We're going to, after that, simply render to the screen like that,
如果一切都做好了 如果我在正确的目录中--
and if all is done and well, and if I'm in the right directory--
但这并没有奏效
it did not work.
再次确保保存您的工作
Make sure you save your work, again.
哦 我不需要上课
Oh, I did not require class.
我的错
My bad.
同样 我们需要这样做 因为我们已将其添加到我们的目录中
So also, we need to do this since we added that to our directory.
我也没有把Bird.png也包括在内
And I did not include the bird.png as well.
所以我要继续下去 并做到这一点
So I'm going to go ahead, and do that.
我要从下一本目录中借用一下
I'm going to borrow that from the next directory.
这应该是我们需要做的全部工作 并尝试调用方法
That should be all we need to do, and attempt to call method.
呈现空值
Render a null value.
有意思的
Interesting.
我不是救了小鸟吗？
Did I not save bird?
我没有救小鸟
I did not save bird.
我们走吧
There we go.
我们做到了
We did it.
所以并不是特别有趣 但我们正在采取措施
So not particularly interesting, but we're making steps.
记住保存您的工作
Remember to save your work.
正如我们所看到的 我不这样认为
As we can see, I do not.
但我们正在取得进展
But we're making progress.
我们有我们要控制的实体
We have our entity that we will control.
从视觉上看 我们正在非常接近 但许多重要的细节都缺失了
Visually, we're getting very close, but a lot of important details are missing.
我们认为下一步应该是什么？
What should be the next step, do we think?
观众：让我们让他跳跃和摔倒
AUDIENCE: Let's get him jumping and falling.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错 我们会在他们的帮助下做到这一点
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly, and we'll do that with the help
这一概念在平台游戏和许多游戏中都很常见
of a notion that's common in platformers, and a lot of games,
事实上 但重力
actually, but gravity.
我们认为如何在2D游戏开发的背景下模拟重力？
How do we think we can simulate gravity in the context of 2D game development?
观众：只是默认的 以恒定的速度下降
AUDIENCE: Just by default, falling at a constant rate.
科尔顿·奥格登：我们当然可以这么做
COLTON OGDEN: We could do that, certainly,
这实际上就是我们将要做的事情
and that's effectively what we will be doing.
我们将使用我们上周使用过的东西 即
We'll be using something that we used last week, which
是速度 增量y 并将这个速度应用于我们的鸟类y
was velocity, delta y, and applying that velocity to our birds y,
一帧接一帧 这会给人一种坠落的错觉
frame by frame, and that will give it the illusion of falling.
现在 以恒定的速度下落并不能准确地反映重力的实际作用
Now, falling at a constant rate isn't accurate to what gravity actually does.
我们想要做的 可能是一次又一次的引力
What we want to do, probably, is some gravity over and over again.
以某种恒定值增加我们的重力
Increment our gravity by some sort of constant value
因此 就像在现实生活中一样 事情下降得越来越快
so that just like in real life, things fall faster, and faster,
然后我们想把它加到我们的y值上
and then we want to add that to our y value.
所以我将继续下去 现在开始在Bird3中实现它
So I'm going to go ahead, and start implementing that now in bird3.
回购错误
Wrong repo.
所以小鸟3号 我们拥有我们以前拥有的一切
So bird3, we have everything that we had from before,
除了现在 我将继续 在main.lua中 在我们的更新函数中
except now, I'm going to go ahead, and in main.lua, in our update function,
这才是我们真正想要的
this is where we're actually going to want
执行更新逻辑以使速度应用于鸟
to perform the update logic for making the velocity apply to the bird.
我们将把它推迟到鸟类课
We're going to defer that to the bird class.
我们将假设在我们的BIRD类中有一个名为UPDATE的方法
We're going to assume that we have a method called update in our bird class,
我们很快就会实施 这实际上是
which we're going to implement shortly, and that's actually
我们在主课上所要做的就是
all we need to do in our main class.
而拥有可以委托所有这些工作的课程的好处是
And the beauty of having classes that you can delegate all this work
TO 您的主文件 尽管它仍然变得相当大--它有108行--
to, your main file, though it's still getting quite large-- it's 108 lines--
它不是200、300、400、数千行代码 因为我们能够
it's not 200 , 300, 400, thousands of lines of code because we're able
破解这段代码 并将其封装到其他地方
to break out this code, and encapsulate it elsewhere.
所以这一次我要记住保存它
So I'm going to remember to save it this time,
然后我将进入Bird.Lua文件
and then I'm going to go into the bird.lua file
在该目录中 这与评论相同
in that directory, which is the same with comments
因为我是从官方回购上下载的 同样的鸟码
because I loaded it from the official repo, the same bird code
我们之前写过的
that we wrote before.
我要继续下去 做几件事
I'm going to go ahead, and do a couple of things.
所以我要做的第一件事是定义一个常量
So the first thing that I'm going to do is define a constant.
所以我以前提到过重力
So I mentioned gravity before.
重力将是一个恒定值 就像它在现实生活中一样
Gravity is going to be a constant value just like it is in real life.
我要把它定义为20
I'm going to define it to 20.
它只是一个任意值
It's just some arbitrary value.
这是一种我觉得正确的价值观
This is a value that I decided felt right,
但您可以随心所欲地调整它
but you can tune this however you want.
做这件事没有对错之分
There's no right or wrong way to do it.
重力越小 它下落的速度就越慢
The less the gravity is, the slower it'll fall,
你越觉得自己在外太空 或者在月球上
and the more you'll feel like you're sort of in outer space, or on the moon,
或者诸如此类的
or whatnot.
我们还将继续 并定义--
We're going to also go ahead, and define--
回想一下 我们需要一些方法来跟踪
recall that we need some way to keep track
我们的鸟是如何坠落的
of how our how our bird is falling.
我们需要一个速度 一个y速度
We want a velocity, a y velocity.
这将更新我们每一帧的位置
This is going to update our position each frame,
它会让人感觉我们在坠落
and it's going to make it feel like we're falling.
所以我们要把初始速度设为0
So we're going to set our initial velocity to 0.
这只鸟只会在中间
The bird's just going to be in the middle.
它还不会掉下来
It's not going be falling yet.
我们不想做的是应用这个速度
What we don't want to do is apply this velocity.
记住 在我们的主文件中 我们假设我们有一个更新函数
So remember, in our main file we assumed that we had an update function,
但我们还没有真正实施它
but we haven't actually implemented it yet.
所以我们现在就要这么做了
So we're going to do that right now.
我们要说的是鸟食DT
We're going to say birdupdate dt.
我们将在主文件中使用的同一dt中传递它
We're going to pass it in the same dt that we use in our main file,
接下来我们要说的是 我们的速度
and we're going to go ahead, and just say our velocity
等于我们当前的速度加上重力乘以增量时间
is equal to our current velocity plus gravity times delta time.
我们只需要用增量时间来衡量重力
We're just going to scale gravity by delta time.
所以它将移动相同的量 无论
So it will move the same amount no matter
无论我们以每秒10帧还是每秒60帧的速度运行
whether we're running at 10 frames per second or 60 frames per second.
然后我们将继续--
And then we're going to go ahead--
我们有一个速度 但它实际上并没有改变我们的y值
we have a velocity, but it's not actually changing our y value.
Y值是最终在屏幕上移动我们的东西
The y value is what ultimately moves us on the screen.
所以我们需要将新的增量y应用到y上
So we need to apply our new delta y to our y.
所以我们要继续下去 就这么做
So we're going to go ahead, and just do that.
得到了 加上自己的点
Self.y gets self.y way plus self dot delta y, dy.
所以如果我回到Bird3 假设我保存了一切
And so if I go back into bird3, assuming I saved everything,
我们应该直接跳到屏幕上 我们就是这么做的
we should just fall straight to the screen, which we do.
不是特别有用 但请注意 它可能有点难说
Not terribly useful, but notice it's slightly hard to tell, maybe,
但它确实一帧一帧地移动得越来越快 因为
but it does move faster, and faster, frame by frame because that delta
和我们的y一样增加 这个增量y也在增加
y is increasing as well as our y, and that delta y is getting
适用于我们的y 一帧接一帧
applied to our y, frame by frame.
我会再做一次
I'll do it one more time.
只是看起来很有趣
It's just funny to look at.
好了 我们有了基本的重力
All right, so we have basic gravity.
超基本计算
Super basic computation.
只需跟踪某个重力常数
Just keep track of some gravity constant, delta y,
增加它 并将它应用于y 这就给了你重力
increase that, and apply that to your y, and that gives you gravity.
但是Flappy Bird会跳
But Flappy Bird can jump.
所以我们需要找到一种方法来对抗地心引力
So we need to find a way to defy gravity.
所以我们要做的是--在鸟4中 我们
So we're going to do the-- in bird4, we're
我们把这叫做反重力更新
going to call this the anti-gravity update,
我们将讨论如何才能真正做到这一点
and we're going to talk about how we can actually get that going.
所以我找到了这张图 我觉得很合适
So I found this diagram, which I felt was pretty apt,
它还涵盖了我们今天讨论的其他一些概念
and it also covers a few of the other concepts we're talking about today.
但是看这里 这个重力 这是我们之前定义的常量
But see here, this gravity, that's the constant we had just defined before,
20美元或更多 这就适用于
the 20 or whatever, and this gets applied
你想让它值多少就值多少
at whatever value you want it to be.
这将逐帧应用于您的y
This gets applied frame by frame to your y.
我们想要的是这个
What we want is this.
这里的矢量是跳跃速度
This vector here is jump velocity.
我们想要一些价值来抵消我们一直在积累的重力
We want some value to counteract this gravity that we've been accumulating.
那么 我们认为我们可以如何着手做这件事呢？
So how do we think we can go about doing this?
我们可以将重力设置为某个负值 或许是一个高值
We can set gravity to some, perhaps, negative value, a high value.
这将产生一帧一帧的效果
And that will have the effect of frame by frame,
如果我们从某个正值开始 这会使我们在y轴上下降
if we go from some positive value, which is taking us down on the y-axis,
然后我们一帧接一帧地取负值
and we go to a negative value, frame by frame,
它会说 假设我们从负5开始
it's going to say-- let's say that we start at negative 5.
我们把它的速度设为负5
We set it's velocity to negative 5 it's going
要将y设置为负--它将设置为+负5像素
to set y to negative-- it's going to set it to plus negative 5 pixels
加上负4.9像素 4.8像素
plus negative 4.9 pixels, 4.8 pixels.
它将以相当快的速度以一系列像素拍摄我们
It's going to shoot us up pretty fast in a series of pixels,
但由于我们是一帧一帧地应用重力 这个值
but since we're applying gravity frame by frame, this value
我们之前设定的 20 它将会产生这样的效果--
that we set before, 20, it's going to have the effect--
是三角洲时间的20倍
20 times delta time.
因此 实际上 它被除以60
So it gets, effectively, divided by 60.
它将再次抵消这一点
It's going to counteract this again.
所以我们会以相当快的速度上升 但重力
So we're going to shoot up pretty fast, but gravity
将立即开始站稳脚跟
is going to start taking hold immediately after,
我们将开始获得鸟类跳跃的效果
and we're going to start getting the effect of our bird jumping,
然后摔倒在地上
and then falling down to the ground.
这张图还显示了其他几件事
A couple of other things that this diagram shows,
我认为这很酷 这个管子缺口
which I thought were pretty cool, this pipe gap
距离 这是我们将要讨论的很好的东西
distance here, something that we'll be talking about pretty
不久 因为需要定义这一点 以便我们可以抵消我们的管道
shortly because this needs to be defined so that we can offset our pipes.
管道分离 这是我们将讨论的另一件事
Pipe separation, it's another thing we'll be talking about.
还有管道宽度 这只是一个内在值
And also pipe width, which is just an intrinsic value
我们将使用的管状精灵的特征
characteristic of the pipe sprite we'll be using,
但我认为这是非常恰当的
but I thought it was very apt.
纽约大学做了一篇不错的文章 如果你想看的话
NYU did a nice article, if you want to look
在这里 关于探索游戏空间
at this, about exploring game space.
他们通过计算确定了什么才是一只会飞的鸟
They computationally determined what would make a Flappy Bird
难度或非难度级别 并对Flappy Bird级别进行动态评级
level difficult or not, and rated Flappy Bird levels that were dynamically
是基于某种规模生成的
generated based on some sort of scale.
所以如果你好奇的话 可以在幻灯片中找到
So if you're curious, it's in the slides,
但我认为这是一个很酷的发现 因为我正在组织这次演讲
but I thought it was a cool find as I was putting together this lecture.
所以我们需要做的就是 简单地给重力增加一些负值
So what we need to do is then, simply, add some negative value to gravity.
负反重力
Negative sort of anti-gravity.
所以我们要继续这样做
So we're going to go ahead do that.
所以在我这里的迷你回购的第四只鸟中
So in bird4 of the little mini repo that I have here,
我们将首先在主干道上继续前进
we're going to go ahead in main, first.
我们想要做的一件事是因为这件事的另一部分
One thing that we want to do is because another part of this
就是接受用户的输入 能够跳跃
is taking input from the user, being able to jump,
我们希望能够检测到他们是否按下了空格键
we want to be able to detect whether they've pressed space.
但如果我们想要检测我们曾经的每一个实体的输入
But if we want to detect input for every single entity that we ever--
在这样的情况下 这并不是特别重要
in an instance like this, it's not terribly important,
但假设我们有20或30种不同的实体
but let's say we have 20 or 30 different kinds of entities,
它们都有自己的输入处理
and they all have their own input handling,
我们不想让它堵塞我们的主管道 这是必然的
we don't want to clog our main with that, necessarily.
所以我们可以把它献给--
So we can dedicate that--
我应该说 把它委托给代码的另一个部分
delegate that, I should say, to another section of the code.
在这种情况下 我们可以把我们的鸟儿输入
In this case, we can sort of put our birds input
和我们的鸟类班一起来处理 对
handling together with our bird class, right,
并阐述了类的模型 对代码和数据的控制
and expound upon the model of the class, taking control of the code and data
对于我们场景中的特定对象
for that particular object in our scene.
所以我们要做的就是在我们的爱中
So what we're going to do is in our love.load,
我要继续下去 在这里做一些事情
I'm going to go ahead, and do something here.
我将继续设置love.keyboard.keysPressed
I'm going to go ahead and set love.keyboard.keysPressed
等于一张桌子
equals a table.
而我所做的只是在一张由Love定义的桌子上添加内容
And what I'm doing is just adding onto a table that Love defined.
这叫爱情键盘
It's called love.keyboard.
我将自己的值添加到它中 称为KeysPressed
I'm adding my own value into it called keysPressed,
我要把它分配给一张空桌子
and I'm assigning it to an empty table.
所以我们要做的是--
So what we're going to do--
这是爱作为它的SDK的一部分给我们的一部分
this is now part of what Love gives us as part of its SDK,
但这是我们自己创造的东西
but it's something that we've created ourselves,
你可以这样做 因为在Lua 基本上所有的东西
and you can do this because in Lua, basically everything
在基本变量之外 只有表 并且您可以操作表
beyond basic variables are just tables, and you can manipulate tables
随心所欲
however you want.
在本例中 love.key是一张表
In this case, love.keyboard is a table.
我只是添加了一个名为keysPressed的新键
I'm just adding a new key called keysPressed,
我把它分配给我自己的一张空桌子
and I'm assigning it to an empty table of my own.
稍后我们将看看它是如何实际使用的
And we're going to see how this is actually used in just a moment.
所以我将在这里继续我们的按键功能--
So I'm going to go ahead in our keyPressed function here--
该函数在用户每次按下游戏中的键时被调用
this function is called every time a user presses a key in the game,
但我会用它的
but I'm going to use it.
因为它做到了这一点 我可以继续下去 只做这样的事情
Because it does that, I can go ahead, and just do something like this.
Love.keyboard.keysPressed Key为True 其含义在此表中
Love.keyboard.keysPressed key gets true, and what that means is in this table
我们刚刚定义的 我们自己创建的 任何时候用户
that we've just defined, we've created ourselves, anytime the user
按任何键 因为会为您调用love.keyPressed
presses any key, because love.keyPressed gets called for you,
我们可以放心 无论如何 这里都会有人居住
we can safely rest assured that this is going to get populated no matter
他们按下什么键 因为这只是一种
what key they press because it's just something
Love2D会照顾你的
that Love2D takes care for you.
但它直到现在才被储存起来
But it's not getting stored until now.
现在我们实际上要跟踪它
Now we're actually going to keep track of it
原因很快就会显现出来
in our own table for reasons that will become apparent very shortly.
这段代码的下一部分是定义一个定制函数
The next part of this code is defining a custom function.
因此 这其中的推动力是爱定义了几个功能
So the impetus for this is Love defines a couple of functions.
它定义了一个名为love.keyboard.isdown的函数
It defines a function called love.keyboard.isdown,
它接受一些关键的值 并且您可以
which takes in some key value, and you can
使用它来测试连续输入 就像我们在上一节课中所做的那样
use it to test for continuous input, which we did in the last lecture.
我们在说 如果UP现在是DOWN 或者DOWN是DOWN
We were saying hey, if up is down right now, or down is down,
然后我们需要相应地更新y速度
then we need to update our y velocity accordingly.
但它没有这样的机制 比如说
But it doesn't have a mechanism like this for let's say,
我们想要在主文件之外的某个文件中检查
we want in some file other than main, to check
因为如果一个键只按了一次
for if a key was just pressed one time.
它有这个函数love.keyPressed 它接受一个密钥
It has this function, love.keyPressed, which takes a key,
这将触发它 但我们不能在此函数之外访问它
and that will trigger it, but we can't access this outside of this function
因为如果我们在Bird.Lua中定义这个函数
because if we define this function in bird.lua,
它将覆盖此实现
it's going to overwrite this implementation.
我们不一定要担心其他文件
And we don't necessarily want to have to worry about other files
覆盖这些函数 因为谁知道呢--
overwriting these functions because who knows--
尤其是如果你在一个团队里 谁知道呢
if you're on a team, especially, who knows
谁被覆盖了love.key按下了 以及在哪个模块中
who's overwritten love.keyPressed, and what module in,
以及它被加载的顺序 以及实际有效的函数
and what order does it get loaded in, and what functions actually valid.
我们将通过赋予自己能力来解决这个问题
We're going to take care of this problem by giving ourselves the ability
测试是否已在最后一帧上按下键
to test for whether a key has been pressed on the last frame
通过实现我们也添加到键盘命名空间的函数
by implementing a function that we are also adding to the keyboard namespace,
我们自己的键盘桌 叫做wasPressed
the keyboard table ourselves, called wasPressed.
它需要一把钥匙 它要做的就是
And it's going to take a key, and all it's going to do
就是检查我们之前创建表
is check that table that we created before.
它会说如果love.keyboard.keysPressed键 那么
It's going to say if love.keyboard.keysPressed key, then
返回True 否则返回False
return true, else return false.
实际上 您可以只返回love.keyboard.keysPressed键
And you could actually just return love.keyboard.keysPressed key,
这将是一模一样的事情
and it will be the exact same thing.
因此 这样做的效果是
And so what this has the effect of doing is
说 好的 因为在我们即将看到的更新上--
saying, OK, because on the update, which we're about to see--
事实上 我可能应该在此之前这样做 这样所有这些都被捆绑在一起
actually, I should probably do that before so this all gets tied together.
在Love的最后 我们要做最后一件事
At the end of love.update, we're going to do one last thing,
这就是重置表格 因为我们只想逐帧检查
and that's reset that table because we want to just check frame by frame.
我们有一个表 一个全局表 我们已经创建
So we have a table, a global table, that we've created
以检查是否按下了某个键
to check for whether a key is pressed.
我们有一个Love2D提供的回调函数 允许我们这样做
We have a callback function that Love2D gives us that allows us to do that.
所以每次按下一个键 我们就会
So every time a key gets pressed, we're going
只需将该键添加到该表 并将其设置为True
to just add that key to that table, and set it to true.
现在 我们可以使用此函数随时简单地查询该表
Now, we can just simply query that table anytime we want to with this function
我们已经创建了一个名为love.keyboard.wasPressed的键 它
that we've created called love.keyboard.wasPressed key, which
最后一帧的意思是 那个键按下了吗？
means on the last frame, was that key pressed?
基本上返回的是真还是假
Basically return whether it's true or false.
现在 唯一的问题是我们没有冲洗它
Now, the only problem is we're not flushing it.
我们永远不会将其设置为假
We're not ever setting that to false.
如果我们只需按下键盘上的所有键
That's has the effect of if we just press all the keys on our keyboard,
在我们重新初始化表之前 这些都是正确的
those will always be true until we re-initialize the table
到某个空值 这就是我们在这里所做的
to some empty value, which is what we do here.
在检测到所有输入之后进行的更新上
On the update, which takes place after all inputs been detected,
我们要把那张桌子又放到一张空桌子上
we're going to just set that table to an empty table again.
在下一帧 它将--无论我们按下什么键 那些
And on the next frame, it's going to-- whatever keys we pressed, those
将被设置为True 然后我们可以根据需要在此处查询该表
will get set to true, and then we can just query that table here as needed,
以及今后的任何更新
and any update henceforth.
那么 有没有人对这是如何运作的有任何疑问？
So does anybody have any questions as to how this is operating?
因此 我们的最终驱动因素
And so the ultimate driving factor for us
至于我们为什么要这样做 为什么我们想要
as to why we want to do this, why we want
为了进行跟踪该全局输入表的工作
to put in the work to keep track of this global input table,
这样我们就可以真正地查询输入 即基于其他文件的单键输入
is so that we can actually query input, single key input based in other files
在Main.Lua之外 因为目前 所有
outside of main.lua because currently, all
我们能做的检查单键按下是在主线上 Lua
we can do to check for single key presses is look in main.lua,
但这不是我们想要做的
but that's not what we want to do.
我们将继续访问我们的Bird.lua 在我们的更新函数中
We're going to go ahead and go to our bird.lua, and in our update function,
这才是我们真正需要付出努力的地方
this is where we actually get to use our efforts,
并假设如果love.keyboard.wa按下空格
and say if love.keyboard.wasPressed space,
这是我们实际上想要允许我们跳跃的关键
which is the key that we want to actually allow us to jump,
去吧 把自己的生命设定为--
go ahead and set self dy to--
当我们按空格键时 应该将self.dy设置为什么？
what should we set self.dy to when we press spacebar?
它应该是正值还是负值？
Should it be a positive or a negative value?
观众：没有
AUDIENCE: Negative.
科尔顿·奥格登：负值
COLTON OGDEN: A negative value.
我们会将其设置为负5 我们可能应该
We'll set it to negative 5, and we should probably
把它定义为一个反重力常数
define this as an anti-gravity constant up here.
但为了速度起见 我们就说self.dy得到负5
But just for the sake of speed, we'll say self.dy gets negative 5.
我确实这么说过 对吧？
And I did say that, right?
我确实这么说过
I did say that.
我要继续往前走 走进鸟巢
I'm going to go ahead, and go into bird4.
继续运行此示例
Go ahead and run this example.
看看这个 我们在跳
And look at that, we're jumping.
但我们仍然可以掉到地面上
But we can still fall through the ground,
而且我们没有任何真正的游戏可玩
and we don't have any real game play.
但我们已经走了很长一段路
But we've come a long ways.
现在我们已经接受了单键输入 否则
Now we've taken single key input that we otherwise
没有能力在Love2D中做到这一点 而我们已经
didn't have the ability to do in Love2D, and we've
仅仅通过跟踪我们的全局输入状态就可以实现
made it possible by just keeping track of our global input state,
每次更新都会刷新
and flushing it every update.
那么 有没有人对它的工作原理有任何疑问？
So does anybody have any questions as to how that works?
好的
OK.
所以Flappy Bird的另一个主要视觉组件
So the other big major visual component of Flappy Bird
就是我们在屏幕上看到的这些管子
are these pipes that we see here on the screen.
我们在那里有两个管道 但屏幕上充满了无限的管道
We have two pipes there, but the screen is filled with infinite pipes.
那么 有没有人对我们如何实现这一点有什么直觉呢？
So does anybody have any instinct as to how we can implement this?
嗯 我们很快就会知道了 但我只想说我们需要一个新的雪碧
Well, we'll see before long, but suffice to say we'll need a new sprite.
我们需要某种方法来跟踪
We'll need some sort of way of keeping track
何时产卵 因为它们会在一段时间后产卵
of when to spawn them because they'd sort of spawn after a period of time,
这将是我们的差距
and that will be our gap.
如果我们让它永远地生下去 会发生什么呢？
And then what will happen if we just let it spawn forever and ever?
观众：你必须在他们离开的时候摧毁他们？
AUDIENCE: You have to destroy them as they go?
科尔顿·奥格登：我们这样做是因为如果我们不这样做
COLTON OGDEN: We do because if we don't do
在一段时间后 我们会分配内存
that, after a certain period of time, we're allocating memory
对于这些管道中的每一个
for each of these pipes.
不是一吨的内存 只是本质上 x y 一个宽度和一个高度
Not a ton of memory, just essentially, an x, a y, a width, and a height.
而是因为它们引用的都是相同的--
But because they all reference the same--
他们将引用相同的精灵图像 但如果有足够的时间
they will reference the same sprite image, but given enough time,
最终 您将分配一定数量的字节
eventually you're going to allocate a certain number of bytes
这将超过您的计算机内存或分配的内存量
that will exceed your computer's memory, or the amount of allocated memory,
你要么无限地挂着 要么崩溃
and you'll either hang infinitely, or crash.
因此 我们想要在他们离开的同时摧毁他们
And so we want to destroy them as they go as well.
因此 我们将继续 并查看最终的实时编码示例
So we're going to go ahead, and look at the final live coded example
只是因为从现在开始 这会有点太多了
just because from here on out, it's going to be a little bit much.
我要走了 先去Main Lua
I'm going to go ahead, and go to main.lua first.
所以把我的笔记整理好
So just get my notes in order.
我们想做的第一件事是--
The first thing that we want to do--
哦 其实我也买错了
oh, I'm actually in the wrong repo too.
我向你道歉
I apologize.
我在发行回购中
I was in the distro repo.
我想成为划痕回收员
I want to be in the scratch repo.
所以我要继续 进入Main 我将需要管道
So I'm going to go ahead, go into main, and I'm going to require pipe.
现在 我们还没有管道 但这是一个完美的例子
Now, we don't have a pipe yet, but this is a perfect example of how
我们可以继续抽象我们的游戏
we can keep abstracting our game.
我们有一节鸟类课 但我们也应该
We have a bird class, but we should also probably
我有一个管道类 因为管道在我们的游戏中是一种不同类型的实体
have a pipe class because a pipe is a distinct type of entity in our game
世界
world.
我们可以将它建模为一个单元 我们可以赋予它功能
We can model it as a unit, we can give it functions,
我们可以给它数据 把它想象成一根管道
we can give it data, and think about it in terms of it being a pipe,
不是XY、宽度、高度等的集合
not being a set of xy, width, height, et cetera.
无论您想要将什么数据归因于它 我们
Whatever data you want to ascribe to it, we
可以把它抽象出来 用更抽象的术语思考 这将
can abstract that out, and think in more abstract terms, which will
让我们能够更好地扩大规模
allow us to scale a little bit better.
所以我们将继续 并假设我们有一个管道类
So we're going to go ahead, and assume that we have a pipe class.
我将继续 并立即将其添加到我们的文件夹中
I'm going to go ahead, and add it to our folder here right now.
所以创建一个新文件 pipe.lua 我要
So do a new file, pipe.lua, and I'm going
继续 并在这里引用一下音符
to go ahead, and reference to notes here for just a second.
所以管道类实际上非常简单
So the pipe class is actually quite simple,
就像最初的鸟类课一样
just like the bird class was initially.
我们不需要跟踪大量的数据
We don't need to keep track of a lot of data,
但我们确实想要跟踪一些事情
but we do want to keep track of a few things.
所以这只鸟--只会有一只鸟出来
So the bird-- there's only ever going to be one bird out
一次 但是有了管子 我们就会把它们生出来
at once, but with the pipes, we're going to be spawning them over,
一遍又一遍
and over again.
所以如果我们分配给他们--
And so if we allocate them--
对于我们实例化的每个管道 如果我们分配一个新的映像
for each pipe that we instantiate, if we allocate a new image,
这可能不是很有效率 对吧？
this is probably not super efficient, right?
我们使用的是相同的数据
We're using the same exact data.
我们有一堆管子
We have a bunch of pipes.
我们真的只需要一个精灵
We only really need one sprite.
所以在init函数之外--就在哪里
So outside of the init function-- so just below where
我们声明管道是一个类 我们是
we're declaring that pipe is a class, we're
接下来我们将创建一个局部变量 该变量仍然
going to go ahead and create a local variable that is still
作用域为此文件 但只有
scoped to this file, but there's only ever going
是这个物体的一个副本
to be one copy of this object.
我们将把它命名为--
We're going to go ahead and call it--
假设我们在此文件夹中有pipe.png
say that we have pipe.png in this folder,
这是从功能中分离出来的
and this is separated out from the functions
我们将在这里定义 但这
that we're going to be defining in here, but this
具有创建半全局图形对象的效果
has the effect of creating a semi global graphics object,
即使它包含在这个类文件中
even though it's contained within this class file.
它不能在这个类文件之外访问
It's not accessible outside of this class file
因为我们不需要这样
because we don't need it to be.
但它也不是每次都被实例化 因为回想一下
But it's also not being instantiated every single time because recall,
如果我们看一下Bird.Lua 我们只是在设置它
if we look at bird.lua here, we're just setting it
As self.Image获得love.graph ics.newImage Bird.png
as self.image gets love.graphics.newImage bird.png.
这将产生每次都分配一个新图像的效果
This will have the effect of allocating a new image every time
我们创建了一个鸟对象
we create a bird object.
但我们只创建了一个鸟对象 所以它并不是一个真正重要的设计
But we only ever create one bird object, so it's not really an important design
考虑到我们会说 也许我们应该创造一个半全球化的形象
consideration for us to say, maybe we should create a semi global image up
这里
here.
在这种情况下 这并不重要
It's not important in this context.
对于更大的项目来说 这样做可能是一种不错的风格 但只是
Probably good style to do so anyway for larger projects, but just
这是这里的一个考虑因素
a consideration for here.
这不是我们需要担心的事
Not really something we need to worry about.
但是的 一定要试着拿到一笔资产
But yes, definitely try to take an asset,
并引用它 而不是尽可能多次地分配它
and reference it rather than allocate it as many times as possible.
我们希望我们的烟斗可以滚动
We want our pipes to scroll.
因此 我们需要某种价值
So we need some sort of value.
就像我们处理背景一样 我们
Just like we did with the backgrounds, we
需要一些值来跟踪这些管道是否正在滚动
need some value that keeps track of whether these pipes are scrolling,
它可以是一个常量值
and it can be a constant value.
这一次我们直接把它称为负60
We're going to directly call it negative 60 this time,
而不是在我们稍后将其添加到我们的立场时予以否定
and not negate it when we add it to our position later on.
所以PIPE_SCROLL负60 我们可以直接加到我们的x上 或者加到我们的--
So PIPE_SCROLL negative 60, we can just add it directly to our x, or to our--
是的 在这种情况下 只给我们的x 而且它
yeah, in this case, just to our x, and it
当然 会有-增量时间
will have the-- times delta time, of course,
这将产生转移的效果
and that will have the effect of shifting
它离开是因为它是负数
it left because it's a negative number.
我们将在这里定义init函数
We'll define the init function here.
所以 通过管道初始化
So pipe init.
在init函数中 我们要做几件事
Within the init function, we're going to do a couple of things.
所以是x
So it's x.
X应该在哪里？
Where should the x be?
比方说 如果我们希望管道产生 x应该设置为多少
What should the x be set to, let's say, if we want the pipe to spawn
超出屏幕右边缘？
beyond the right edge of the screen?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：虚拟宽度 你还可以
COLTON OGDEN: Virtual width, and you could also
假设虚拟宽度加上一些数字 如果你想的话
say virtual width plus some number if you wanted to.
因为它被设置为0 0 所以它将有
Because it's set to 0,0, it's going to have
你不会在实例化的画面上看到它
the-- you won't see it on the frame that it gets instantiated,
但是的 虚拟宽度或虚拟宽度加上某个常量值 或一些
but yes, virtual width or virtual width plus some constant value, or some
您已提前分配的值
value that you've allocated ahead of time.
我们只需将其设置为虚拟宽度
We'll just set it to virtual width.
所以一旦管道被初始化 它就是不可见的
So as soon as the pipe gets initialized, it will be invisible,
但它会出现在屏幕的右边
but it's going to be right on the right edge of the screen.
我们的y值呢？
What about our y value?
首先 让我们看看图像是什么样子的 这样我们就可以看到了
First of all, let's take a look at what the image looks like so we can see.
它将出现在我们的.
It's going to be in our--
我不认为我在那个目录中有实际的图像
I don't think I have the actual image in that directory.
所以我要来这里
So I'm going to come here.
我去拿烟斗
I'm going to grab the pipe.
这就是管子的样子
This is what the pipe looks like.
让我们看看我能不能把它扩大一点
Let's see if I can expand it a little bit.
所以它有点高
So it's kind of tall.
如果我们想要 我们应该把它放在哪里
Where should we probably place it if we wanted
它看起来像飞鸟吗？
it to look similar to Flappy Bird?
很可能是在屏幕的下端
Probably towards the lower end of the screen.
我们也可以幻想它 我们甚至可以
We can get fancy with it too, and we can even maybe
让它像Flappy Bird那样随机化
make it randomized just like Flappy Bird.
因此 我们将继续 并做到这一点
So we'll go ahead, and do that.
我将继续复制 并将其放入我们的临时文件夹中
I'm going to go ahead, and copy this, and put it into our scratch folder
这里
here.
回到init函数 我将继续 并设置self.y
Back in the init function, I'm going to go ahead, and set self.y too.
因为我们想谈的是程序生成
Because we want to talk about procedural generation,
这将是我们第一次尝试如何随机化这一点
this will be sort of our first foray into how we randomize this.
我们将使用上周使用的函数
We'll be using the function that we used last week,
这是一个无处不在的函数
and this is a ubiquitous function.
你会在你使用的任何框架或游戏引擎中随处可见--
You'll see this everywhere in any framework or game engine you use--
数学 随机的
math.random.
我们希望它是屏幕的下半部分
We want it to be the lower half of the screen.
假设虚拟高度除以4是上限 也许
So let's say virtual height divided by 4 is the upper bound, and maybe
虚拟高度减去10作为上限
virtual height minus 10 as the upper bound.
因此 这将产生将其设置为大约四分之一屏幕的效果
So that will have the effect of setting it to roughly a quarter of the screen.
抱歉 虚拟高度除以4是屏幕的最高端
Sorry, virtual height divided by 4 is towards the top end of the screen,
然后虚拟高度减去10就是屏幕的下端
and then virtual height minus 10 is the lower end of the screen.
因此 它实际上将覆盖从低于这一水平的第一季度开始的任何地方
So it's actually going to cover anywhere from the first quarter below that, down
从底部到大约10个像素
to about 10 pixels from the bottom.
观众：你一定要在这里面设置随机种子吗？
AUDIENCE: Do you have to set the random seed in this [INAUDIBLE]
或者你主要做这件事？
or do you do it main?
科尔顿·奥格登：我在美因河畔做
COLTON OGDEN: I do it in main.
因此 在这个文件中 我不确定我这样做是否是为了这个演示
So in this file, I am not sure if I did it for this demonstration.
这肯定是在回购中设定的
It is definitely set in the repo.
我不认为我在这个例子中设置了它 但是 是的 您
I don't think I set it in this example, but yes, you
如果您想让它每次都运行 就会在这里设置随机种子
would set the random seed here if you wanted it to run every time.
抱歉的
Sorry.
问题是 我们是否应该在BIRD文件中设置随机种子
And the question was should we set the random seed in the bird file,
或者我们应该把它设在主星上？
or should we set it in main.lua?
通常 您希望在应用程序的顶级设置它
Typically, you want to set it at the top level of your application.
所以我们要把它放进去--
So we're going to set it in--
我们将继续 并将其设置为Main
we're going to go ahead, and set it in main.
函数本身就在这里 我认为它是从Bird6开始的 从6开始
And the function itself is here, and I think it's starting in bird6, onwards.
所以它将会是--
So it will be--
我没设好吗？
did I not set it?
我可能要到回购的晚些时候才会设置随机种子
I may not have set the random seed until later in the repo.
让我们检查一下Bird12
Let's check bird12.
所以 是的 数学 随机种子 然后是os.time的种子
So yes, math.randomseed, and then seed by os.time,
就像我们上周在课堂上用到的一样
as we used last week in class.
我把它放在这里
I'll set it here.
也许 我们只会运行一次 但它会产生效果
Probably, we'll only run it once, but it'll have the effect.
现在我们可以运行几次 看看管道中的不同之处
Now we can run it several times just to see the difference in the pipes.
让我们回到我们的管道 Lua在这里 我们有x y
Let's go back to our pipe.lua here, and we have the x, we have the y.
因此 这些都是相应地设置的
So those are set accordingly.
我们还想设置宽度
We also want to set the width.
有人记得获取图形对象宽度的函数是什么吗
Does anybody recall what the function is to get a width of a graphics object
它的语法是什么？
and the syntax for that?
所以我们在这里有我们的图像 管道图像
So we have our image up here, pipe image.
它是love.graph ic.newImage pipe.png
It's love.graphic.newImage pipe.png.
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
因此 我们将继续 并将其设置为PIPE_IMAGE冒号getWidth
So we're going to go ahead, and set this to PIPE_IMAGE colon getWidth,
这将成为我们的新--这将使我们能够存储我们的宽度以备
and that will become our new-- that will allow us to store our width for when
我们稍后将使用它
we will use it later.
然后我们还需要一些其他函数
And then we need a few other functions.
所以烟斗会产生 但它不会移动 因为我们还没有
So the pipe will spawn, but it won't move because we haven't
对它进行了任何形式的滚动
applied any sort of scrolling to it.
我们在第五行有滚动的变量
We have the scrolling variable up on line five,
但我们需要将其实际应用到我们的管道中
but we need to actually apply it to our pipe.
所以我们将继续 并创建一个更新函数
So we're going to go ahead, and create an update function.
然后在更新函数中 非常类似于
And then in that update function, very similar to what
我们以前已经见过 pio_scroll乘以增量时间
we've seen before already, PIPE_SCROLL times delta time.
最后 我们想要渲染我们的烟斗
And then lastly, we want to render our pipe.
所以我们将继续 调用我们今天已经看到的函数
So we're going to go ahead, and call a function that we've seen already today,
我们将使用上面的管子图像
love.graphics.draw We're going to use the pipe image up above,
然后我们将继续使用self.x
and then we're going to go ahead, and use self.x,
和自己 这就是我们的烟斗所需要的
and self.y, and that's all we need for our pipe.
让我确保这就是我们真正需要的
And let me make sure that that's all we really need.
所以在主流星中--我们也必须回到主流星 因为我们实际上
So in main.lua-- we've got to go back to main.lua too because we actually
必须开始产卵了
have to start spawning pipes.
所以让我们继续 去--
So let's go ahead, and go to--
让我在这里再次调出我的代码
let me pull up my code here one more time.
在主线上--所以在第59行--
In main-- so on line 59--
抱歉 你看不到的
sorry, you won't see it.
您将在实际发行版代码的第59行中看到它
You'll see it in line 59 in the actual distro code,
但对我来说 情况会略有不同
but for me, it's going to be slightly different.
我们将继续 并创建一个新表
We're going to go ahead, and create a new table
来跟踪我们想要产生的所有管道 因为我们
to keep track of all the pipes that we want to spawn because we
需要一种方法将它们存储在内存中
need a way to store them in memory.
我们不能只设置一个变量来--
We can't just set one variable to--
基本上 在这种情况下几乎像一个动态数组 或者更确切地说是一个链表
basically, almost like a dynamic array in this case, or a linked list rather.
我们要用这张桌子来容纳他们
We're going to use this table just to hold them.
我们不会给他们钥匙的
We're not going to give them keys.
我们只需像我们所做的那样插入它们
We're just going to insert them like we would
例如 只需像在Python中那样使用链接列表即可
do with just a linked list like in Python, for example.
我们要继续前进 我们需要什么
We're going to go ahead, and what do we need
如果我们想让它们在一段时间后产卵怎么办？
to do if we want to have them spawn after a certain period of time?
可能想要一个计时器
Probably want to have some sort of timer.
我们想要记录已经过去了多少时间
We want to keep track of how much time has passed,
也许会有一些时间
and maybe have some sort of amount of time
那是我们产生烟斗的触发点
that's our trigger to spawn of a pipe.
比方说大概两秒钟
Let's say maybe 2 seconds.
所以如果我们将计时器设置为0 它就从0开始
So if we set a timer to 0, it's just start just at 0,
但我们可以一帧一帧地添加
but we can add to this frame by frame.
我们可以将计时器增加增量时间 无论是什么 逐帧增加
We can just increase this timer by delta time, whatever that is, frame by frame.
大概是1/60秒
It'll be about 1/60 of a second.
因此 在60帧之后 我们将有一秒钟的时间
So after 60 frames have passed, we'll get one second.
在120帧之后 我们将有两秒钟的时间
After 120 frames have passed, we'll have two seconds.
在这一点上 我们可以决定好了 现在是时候产生一个新的管道了
At that point, we can then decide OK, now it's time to spawn a new pipe.
让我们继续做这件事吧
Let's go ahead and do that.
因此 我将继续 在我们的更新功能中
So I'm going to go ahead, and in our update function,
我们希望处理此计时器的实际增加
we want to handle the actual increasing of this timer.
所以这很简单--
So it's as simple as--
我确定我把它叫做spawnTimer
and I make sure that I called it spawnTimer.
不 我只是叫它定时器
No, I just called it timer.
让我们继续 并将其命名为spawnTimer
Let's go ahead, and call it spawnTimer.
更具体一点 我们想要什么
Be a little more specific about what we want here.
所以我们的spawnTimer
So our spawnTimer.
然后我们将继续更新
And then we're going to go ahead in our update,
并将spawnTimer设置为等于spawnTimer加上增量时间
and set spawnTimer equal to spawnTimer plus delta time.
然后我们需要做的就是检查
And then what we need to do is then check
我们的产卵计时器是否大于--因为它
is our spawn timer greater than-- because it
以秒为单位跟踪时间 增量时间将为您提供
keeps track of time in seconds, delta time will give you
以秒为单位的分数
a fractional amount in seconds.
所以它将在0.013 或类似的地方
So it will be at 0.013, or something like that.
我们希望跟踪spawnTimer是否已经过了两点 对吗？
We want to keep track of whether spawnTimer has gone past two, right?
因此 如果spawnTimer大于2 我们希望添加一个新管道
So if spawnTimer is greater than 2, we want to add a new pipe.
有人记得Lua中如何添加到表中的函数吗？
Does anybody remember the function for how to add to a table in Lua?
所以它是桌子 插入
So it's table.insert.
因此 Table.Insert将接受一个表
So table.insert will take in a table.
因此 在本例中 我们需要前面分配的管道表
So in this case, we want the pipes table that we allocated before.
然后我们要放入一个新的管道对象
And then we're going to put in a new pipe object.
这就是为调用实例化对象的方式 圆括号
This is how you instantiate an object for call, parentheses.
这将对我们现在的管道产生影响
That will have the effect of now our pipes
表将--每次我们调用它时 它都会得到一个新的索引
table is going to-- every time we call this, it's going to get a new index.
所以它将从1开始
So it's going to start at 1.
LUA表的索引值为1
Lua tables are indexed at 1.
第一次发生这种情况时 index1将
The first time it happens, index1 is going
等于将要启动的新管道对象
to be equal to a new pipe object, which is going to start
它的XY在屏幕的边缘
its xy at the edge of the screen.
那么index2将是完全相同的东西 一个新的管道
Then index2 will be the exact same thing, a new pipe that's
在屏幕的边缘 诸如此类 每次我们
at the edge of the screen, and so on, and so forth every time we
调用表 插入
call table.insert.
一旦我们的产卵计时器超过2 如果我们不想这样做
Once our spawn Timer has exceeded 2, if we want this to not
之后每一帧都会产生一根烟斗 很快就会堵塞我们的世界
spawn a pipe every frame here after, which would quickly clog up our world,
我们希望将产卵计时器重置为0
we want to reset our spawn timer to 0.
所以这将产生现在的效果 它将再等待2秒
So this will have the effect of now, it's going to wait another 2 seconds,
然后这个条件将再次成为真的
and then this condition will be true again,
然后我们可以在场景中添加一个新的管道
and then we can add a new pipe to the scene.
让我们继续来看看--
Let's go ahead and look at--
我们需要在这里添加一组新的逻辑
we're going to need to add a new set of logic here.
事实上 我会把所有这些放在鸟的上面 更新
Actually, I'm going to put all of this above the bird.update,
然后在这下面 我将继续 并做--
and then below that, I'm going to go ahead, and do--
我不确定我们是否已经谈到这一点
I'm not sure if we've covered this already.
我不认为我们有 但如果我们想迭代一个表
I don't think we have, but if we want to iterate over a table,
Lua给了你一个叫做Pair的函数
there's a function that Lua gives you called pairs.
它将为您提供表的所有键值对
It will give you all the key value pairs of a table
然后您可以在迭代它时使用它
that you can then use while you're iterating over it.
类似于在Python中枚举 如果熟悉
Similar to enumerate in Python, if familiar,
不过 这实际上会给你提供关键字 而不仅仅是索引
except this will actually give you the keys rather than just the indices.
所以我们可以对k做 成对的管道做一些主体代码
So we can do for k, pipe in pairs of pipes do some body of code,
然后我们可以访问密钥和其中的管道
and then we have access to the key and the pipe within this.
我们可以只迭代它 并使用它
We can just iterate over it, and use it.
因此 我们要做的第一件事是更新管道
So the first thing we want to do is we want to update our pipe.
因此 对于每个管道 更新它
So for each pipe, update it.
为其指定当前帧的增量时间
Give it the delta time of the current frame.
那么另一个重要的特点是什么呢？
And then what was the other important feature?
因此 这将具有滚动它的效果
So this will have the effect of scrolling it now.
它会把它的x移位 但是
It's going to get its x shifted, but what
我们需要对场景中的每一根烟斗做的另一件重要的事情是吗？
was the other important thing we needed to do with every pipe in our scene?
观众：当x小于0时 我们必须[INAUDIBLE]
AUDIENCE: When x is less than 0, we have to [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
COLTON OGDEN: Yes.
这完全是真的
That is exactly true.
所以我们要做的是 如果pipe.x小于--
So what we're going to do is if pipe.x is less than--
如果我们做的小于0 我们认为会发生什么？
so if we did less than 0, what do we think would happen?
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：我们会看到它立即消失 因为他们
COLTON OGDEN: We would see it instantly disappear because they're
根据左上角的坐标
based on the top left coordinates.
所以我们需要做的就是跟踪它的宽度
So what we need to do is keep track of its width.
所以我们要做的就是说如果pipe.x
So what we'll do is we'll just say if pipe.x
小于负数pipe.width 这将允许管道
is less than negative pipe.width, which will allow the pipe
要一直穿过屏幕的边缘
to go all the way past the edge of the screen,
我们将调用一个名为Table.Remove的函数 该函数接受一个表
we'll call a function called table.remove, which takes a table,
在这种情况下 管道 然后它需要一把钥匙
in this case, pipes, and then it takes a key.
以及我们可以在124号线上获得的密钥
And the key we have access to up above on line 124.
我们可以只说k 这会产生这样的效果
We can just say k, and that will have the effect
把那根烟斗从现场移走
of removing that pipe from the scene.
一旦做完了 我们就可以走了
And then as soon as that's done, we're good to go.
我们现在最不需要做的就是
The last thing that we need to do is currently,
我们实际上并没有将管道绘制到屏幕上
we're not actually drawing the pipe to the screen.
所以在下面的渲染函数中 我们将继续 并在上面--
So down below in our render function, we're going to go ahead, and up above--
在我们做地面之前 因为如果我们正常地做--
before we do the ground, because if we do it normally--
如果我们在铺好地面后再做 这些管道
if we do it after we render the ground, the pipes
看起来就像是层叠在地面上
are going look like they're just kind of layered on top of the ground.
我们希望它看起来像是从地面上伸出来的
We want it to look as if they're sticking out from the ground.
所以我们想要做的是有一个正确的渲染层
So what we want to do is have a correct render layer,
将绘制顺序渲染到屏幕
a render draw order to the screen.
我们画背景 画管子 然后画地面
We draw the background, we draw the pipes, then we draw the ground,
这将产生管道看起来像是伸出的效果
and this will have the effect of looking as if the pipes are sticking out
在地面上
of the ground.
所以我们要做的就是和刚才做的完全一样
So what we'll do is we'll do the exact same thing we just did up
上面通过说for k 管道成对地做管道
above by saying for k, pipe in pairs of pipes do pipe,
然后是我们在PIPE中定义的呈现函数
and then the render function that we defined in pipe.
这将产生迭代的效果
And this will have the effect of iterating
通过我们场景中所有的管道 每个抽签电话
through all the pipes in our scene every draw call,
在它画地面之前画它们 在它画鸟之前
and drawing them before it draws the ground, and before it draws the bird,
这应该就是我们所需要的 来说明这个例子
and that should be all that we need to illustrate this example.
让我确保所有东西都保存好了
Let me make sure everything is saved.
我要继续往前走 走进鸟巢
I'm going to go ahead, and go into bird5.
如果我做的每件事都是正确的 那么在一段时间之后
If I did everything correctly, this should, after a certain period of time,
将正在滚动的管道放到屏幕上 它们是随机的
drop pipes to the screen that are scrolling, and they're randomized.
它们的y值被设置为某个值
Their y value is getting set to some value
在屏幕顶部的四分之一之间
between the top quarter of the screen.
所以从Flappy Bird现在的位置开始 向下
So starting about right where Flappy Bird is right now, down
大约10个像素以上的屏幕宽度 这实际上
about 10 pixels above the width of the screen, which actually,
这看起来像是10个像素以上
that looks like 10 pixels above.
所以这是一个小小的漏洞
So that's a slight bug.
它可能应该在30或40左右
It should probably be something along the lines of 30 or 40.
我们不会在最终发行版中遇到这种情况
We won't encounter that in the final distro
因为它们不会产卵那么低
because they're not set to spawn that low,
但是你可以看到这在某种程度上是我们程序层面的开始
but you can see how this is sort of the beginning of our procedural level
生成系统 我们拥有场景的几乎所有组件
generation system, and we have most all the components of our scene.
现在 在Flappy Bird中 我们通常有两个管子
Now, normally in Flappy Bird, we have two pipes.
我们在上面有一根管道 然后在下面有一根管道
We have a pipe that's above, and then a pipe that's below,
他们是成对的
and they're in pairs.
在下一个例子中 我们实际上将开始说明这一点
In the next example, we're actually going to start illustrating this.
我们将有几对连接在一起的管子
We're going to have pairs of pipes that are joined together,
它们一起滚动
which scroll together.
一旦你飞过它们 你就得了一分
That once you fly through them, you score a point.
但就目前而言 我们拥有我们所有的碎片
But for now, we have all the pieces that we
需要有基本的视觉感才能完成游戏
need in order to have the basic visual sense of the game completed.
我们现在休息五分钟 等我们回来后
We're going to take like a five minute break now, and then once we come back,
我们将深入研究如何将成对的管道引入我们的场景中
we'll actually dive into how we can get pairs of pipes into our scene,
开始打球 做一些其他有趣的事情 比如音乐
and start getting into scoring, and some other fun things like music.
好了 欢迎回来
All right, welcome back.
所以下一部分--
So the next part--
所以在我们确定鸟的背景和管子之前
so before we establish the bird, the background, the pipes,
我们已经准备好了比赛的所有视觉方面
we have all the visual aspects of our game ready to go.
真正要解决的下一个重要问题是
The next important piece of the puzzle to really solve
我们怎么才能开始得分 我们怎么才能
is how can we start scoring our game, and also how can we
让管道与它们在实际游戏中实现的方式相匹配？
get the pipes matching the way that they're implemented in the actual game?
回想一下 它们通常是成对的 如图所示
Which, recall, they're normally in pairs, as illustrated here.
我们也看到在右手边 正如我们到目前为止已经介绍过的那样
And we also see on the right-hand side, as we've covered already so far,
我们有放烟斗的产卵区 在左边
we have the spawn zone for our pipes, and on the left,
我们有我所说的死亡区 在那里
we have what I've labeled the dead zone, where
管道一旦消失就被取消实例化
pipes are de-instantiated once they've gone
越过了它们自身的负宽度
past the negative width of themselves.
但管子是成对的 他们会被移位
But pipes come in pairs, they get shifted,
一旦鸟儿在这些缝隙之间飞翔
and once the bird flies between these gaps,
最终是当他们得到一分的时候
is ultimately when they've scored a point.
因此 我们需要一种将管道配对在一起的方法 并定义这种逻辑
And so we need a way to pair pipes together, and define this logic for how
我们能说出这只鸟是否已经越过了缺口
can we tell whether the bird has gone past the gap,
以及管道是否已被取消实例化
and whether or not the pipes have been de-instantiated.
所以我们要继续下去 我可能会
So we're going to go ahead, and I'm going to probably
停止对其余演示进行实时编码
stop live coding for the rest of the demonstrations
因为它们会变得更复杂一些
because they're going to be a little bit more complex.
但我相信我的代码编辑器在这里
But I believe my code editor is over here.
我要继续 然后打开--
I'm going to go ahead, and open up--
哦 这是我的另一位编辑
oh, this is my other editor.
现在 在基本回购中 我们将继续 并查看完整的示例
So in the base repo now, we're going to go ahead, and look at the full example.
所以在Bird6中 这是管子对的更新--
So in bird6, which is the pipe pair update--
我们现在看到的子文件夹--
our current subfolder that we're looking at--
我们要从美因河开始
we're going to start in main.
所以在Main的第33行
So on line 33 in main.
我们可以看到我们正在获取管道对 它
We can see that we're acquiring pipe pair, which
是我们正在定义的一个新类别
is a new class we're defining.
我们要用以前用过的管子
We're taking the pipe that we had before,
我们正在创建一个新的复合类
and we're creating a new composite class.
所以我们将获取一个将两个管道封装在一起的类
So we're going to take a class that encapsulates two pipes together,
一对管道 我们将用它来更多地思考我们的问题
a pair of pipes, and we're going to use this to think about our problem more
比我们已经拥有的更抽象
abstractly than we already are.
这种抽象的分层是一个非常重要的概念
And this layering of abstractions is a very important concept
在计算机科学中 一般说来 但特别是
in computer science, generally speaking, but especially
在游戏中 您可能拥有由以下对象组合而成的对象
in games where you might have objects that are composites of objects that
是对象的组合 而这些抽象层次结构是
are composites of objects, and these abstract hierarchies are
是什么让程序员在处理事务时保持理智
sort of what keeps programmers sane when dealing
当你有数千行代码时 有这么多级别的代码
with such large levels of-- when you have thousands of lines of code,
这是你真正理解它的唯一方法
it's sort of the only way you can really make sense of it.
所以在第65行 如果我们看--
So on line 65, if we look--
现在 我们将其重命名为管道对 而不是称为管道的表
now, instead of a table that's called pipes, we've renamed it to pipe pairs.
我们不再在场景中存储单个管道
We're no longer going to store individual pipes in our scene.
我们要把这些管子对 我们
We're going to take these pipe pairs that we're
我要创建它们 并将它们存储在我们的表中以及单个单元中
going to create, and store them in our table as well as individual units.
在第71行 我们需要一个变量来跟踪--
On line 71, we need a variable to keep track of the--
我们把它叫做最后一年
we're calling it last y.
此变量的用途是为了让我们
The purpose of this variable is so that we
可以跟踪最后一组管道产生缺口的位置
can keep track of where the last set of pipes spawned their gap.
因为如果我们让我们的差距完全随机的话
Because if we made our gaps completely random,
它将产生一种效果 看起来不像是连续的
it will have the effect of not looking continuous for one,
也有可能是无法击败的
and also potentially being impossible to beat.
我们想要一些光滑的轮廓来填补我们的缝隙
We want some sort of smooth contour to our gaps
这样我们才能合理地飞越它们
so that we can fly through them reasonably,
而且它看起来几乎是预制的 而且很光滑
and that it looks as if it was almost pre-made, and smooth.
所以我们将跟踪一个名为last y的变量
So we're going to keep track of a variable called last y.
我们要从负管高开始
We're going to start it off at negative pipe height.
超出屏幕顶部 加上介于1和80之间的某个值
So up past the top of the screen, plus some sort of value between 1 and 80
和20岁
and 20.
它将大致位于屏幕的顶部
It's going to be roughly towards the top of the screen.
这一点很重要 因为最后一个y是
And this is important because the last y is
我们将会--我们将会翻转我们的雪碧
going to be-- we're going to end up flipping our sprite.
在y轴上翻转的结果是精灵看起来
A flip on the y-axis has the result of the sprite looking
就好像它的整个高度都超过了实际的y
as if it's gone its whole height above where its actual y is,
我们稍后会详细解释为什么
and we'll see in more detail, shortly, why
这最终会以它的方式工作
this ends up working the way it does.
我们要下到132行 在我们的条件下
We're going to go down to line 132, and in our condition,
如果我们的spawnTimer大于2 我们要做的是
if our spawnTimer is greater than 2, what we're going to do
这是我们之前制作管道的地方
is this is where we spawned our pipes before,
但现在我们正在生产成对的管道
but now we're spawning pairs of pipes.
所以我们要设置一个局部变量y
So we're going to set a local variable y.
这将是-
It's going to be--
这是我们上周讲过的夹钳操作
this is the clamp operation that we talked about last week
使用math.max和math.min来应用某种操作
using math.max and math.min to apply some sort of operation.
在本例中 我们将在负20之间添加一个随机值
In this case, we're going to add a random value between negative 20
20的y值
and 20 to whatever our last y value was, which
将有效地将间隙移动负20或20个像素
is going to shift the gap effectively by negative 20 or 20 pixels.
我们要把它夹在负管道高度加10之间
We're going to clamp it between negative pipe height plus 10.
离屏幕顶部大约10个像素
So about 10 pixels from the top of the screen,
然后我们将上限设为虚高减90
and then we're going to set the upper bound to virtual height minus 90
减去管道高度
minus pipe height.
这个负管光只是因为我们在做翻转操作
And this minus pipe light is only because we're doing a flip operation
在我们的精灵的y轴上
on our y-axis for our sprite.
我会更详细地讲
I'll go into it in a little bit more detail
来解释我们为什么要这么做
to try to make it clear as to why we're doing it,
也许我会拿出一些代码来说明它的样子
and maybe I'll take out some codes to illustrate what it looks
就像没有那个操作一样
like without that operation applied.
但基本上 它有从底部90像素的效果
But basically, it has the effect of 90 pixels from the bottom
是鸿沟产生的地方
is where the gap could spawn.
基本上 就是最底下的管子
So basically, the pipe at the very bottom.
回想一下 这个差距就是--
Recall that this gap is where--
该值是间隙本身开始的位置 不一定
this value is where the gap itself begins, not necessarily
管道的起点
where the pipe starts.
它会在负管道高度加10之间
It'll be between negative pipe height plus 10.
基本上 有效地 在屏幕顶部的10个像素之间
Basically, effectively, between 10 pixels from the top of the screen,
在距离屏幕底部90个像素之间
between 90 pixels from the bottom of the screen,
然后我们将应用这个值的随机排列
and then we're going to apply a random permutation of this value.
我们要在负20和20之间加上一个值
We're going to add some value between negative 20 and 20,
这将给我们一个等高线 这将是一个随机的等高线
and that will give us a contour, and it'll be a randomized contour.
136线 我们有一对管子
Line 136, we have pipe pairs.
将桌子插入其中 而不是管道 我们只是添加了一个新管道对
Table insert into that instead of pipes, and we're just adding a new pipe pair,
我们将它设置为y的值
and we're setting it to the value y.
然后管子对接受y值
And then the pipe pair takes in a y value,
而这将是差距的起点
and that will be where the start of the gap is.
以及这将会产生什么效果
And what this will have the effect of doing
它是不是要把一个精灵翻转到缺口上方
is it's going to flip a sprite above the gap
所以我们在缝隙开始处的正上方有一根管道 然后它
so that we have a pipe right above where the gap starts, and then it's
要绘制另一个管道 在该管道下方约90个像素处未翻转
going to draw another pipe unflipped about 90 pixels below that,
这将是它将两者结合在一起的方式
and that will be how it puts the two together.
第144行是一个循环 它只更新我们的对 而不是我们的管道
Line 144 is a loop that just updates our pairs instead of our pipes.
因此 我们在这里所做的只是将其从管道重命名为对 而不是
So all we've done here is just renamed it from pipe to pair, and instead
在管道中 我们使用管道对
of pipes, we're using pipe pairs.
在第153行 我们正在做同样的事情
We are doing the same exact thing here on line 153.
我们已经做了k对成对的管子
We've done for k pair in pairs of pipe pairs.
然后是150行--
And then line 150--
抱歉 175线是我们现在的位置--
sorry, line 175 is where we are--
抱歉 170是我们渲染每对而不是每个管道的位置
sorry, 170 is where we are rendering each pair instead of each pipe.
所以如果我们在这里打开管子对 我们可以看看
And so if we open up pipe pair here, we can take a look
在这堂课上从头开始
at this class from scratch.
所以这是一个新的班级
So it's a new class.
我们要将间隙高度设置为90像素
We're going to set our gap height to 90 pixels,
所以这只是一个任意值 我
and so this is just some arbitrary value that I
就大小而言 Feel是一个相当公平的价值
felt was a pretty fair value in terms of size,
但你可以把它调到你想要的任何地方
but you can tune this to whatever you want.
你可以把这个设置为--
You could set this to--
如果你真的想变得残酷 你可以把它设定在50左右
if you want to be really cruel, you could set it to something like 50.
或者 如果你想对球员非常慷慨
Or if you wanted to be really generous to the player,
你可以把它设置在150左右 然后
you could set it to something like 150, and make
对他们来说 这是相当容易的
it fairly easy for them to get through.
或者作为作业的一部分 你可以随机化它
Or as part of the assignment, you could randomize it
所以它一对一对地变化 你会得到更多
so that it varies pair by pair, and you get more
看起来像是有机的障碍赛道
of an organic looking obstacle course.
它仍然被移动了负20到20个像素
It's still shifted by negative 20 to 20 pixels,
但现在你的差距是不同的 你也可以随机化移位量
but now your gap varies, and you can also randomize the shift amount
如果你也想的话
if you wanted to as well.
假设你想要--
Let's say you wanted--
也许您希望间隔最大为40像素
maybe you want the gaps to be up to 40 pixels
差异而不是20个像素的差异
difference instead of 20 pixels difference
论负值和正值
on negative and positive value.
你也可以很容易地做到这一点
You could easily do that as well.
在第18行 我们只是将x设置为
On line 18 we're just setting our x to just like
我们以前做过 虚拟宽度加32
we did before, virtual width plus 32.
所以我们将其设置为--
So we're setting it to the--
实际上 在我们将其设置为虚拟宽度之前
actually, before we just set it to virtual width.
现在我们将其设置为虚拟宽度加32
Now we're setting it to virtual width plus 32.
两者基本持平
Both are pretty much equal.
这只会让它有一点延迟
This will just give it a little bit of a delay
在它最终出现在屏幕上之前 但你可以有效地
before it ends up going onto the screen, but you can effectively just
这样做 虚拟宽度
do this, virtual width.
在下一行 24 这是我们捆绑在一起的地方
On the next line, 24, this is where we sort of bundled together
我们最终要渲染和更新的管道
the pipes that we're going to end up actually rendering and updating
传到屏幕上
to the screen.
一对管道不是只有一根管道 而是两根管道
Instead of having just one pipe, a pipe pair is two pipes.
我们可以很容易地把这些放在一张桌子里
We can easily put this together in a table.
因此 我们将只创建self.pires
So we'll just create self.pipes.
我们将它设置到一个有两个键的桌子上 上键和下键
We'll set it to a table that has two keys, upper and lower,
上面的管子只是一根管子
and the upper pipe is just a pipe.
请注意 管道有一点不同
And notice one thing is different about pipe.
现在 以前 这是不需要争论的
Now, before, it took no arguments.
这只是一根普通的烟斗
It was just a regular pipe.
管道有其自身的逻辑
Pipes had their own logic.
他们设置自己的x和y
They set their own x and y.
除此之外 他们不需要任何形式的参数化
They didn't need any sort of parametrization beyond that.
这一切都是随机为他们安排的
It was all taken care of for them randomly.
现在 他们拿着一根绳子
Now, they take a string.
这根顶线意味着这将是一根顶管
So this top string means that this would be a top pipe.
也就是说 如果这根管子是顶层管子
So that means that if this pipe is a top pipe,
在管道中可能会有逻辑 现在检查
there's probably going to be logic in pipe that now checks
看看它是顶部还是底部
to see whether it's top or bottom.
如果它是顶部的 那么我们需要把它倒过来
If it's top, then we need to render it upside down.
我们需要将其沿y轴翻转 然后将其设置为self.y
We need to flip it along the y-axis, and then we're going to set it to self.y.
回想一下我们设置了self.y--
And recall that we set self.y--
我们在主航道通过了SELFY
we passed in self.y in main.
实际上 我不确定我有没有提到这点
Actually, I'm not sure if I touched on that.
让我们回到Main这里
Let's go back to main here.
所以如果我们去--
So if we go to--
我需要找出我实际实例化管道的位置
I need to figure out where I actually instantiate the pipes.
在第136行 在我们计算出
Here on line 136, after we've calculated where
我们希望这对管子的间隙是这样的
we want the gap to be for this pipe pair,
我们继续往前 把一对管子插入 y处的管子
we're going to go ahead, and insert into pipe pairs, a pipe pair at y.
计算的范围是--我们基本上取了最后一个y值
Y was the calculation between-- we basically took the last y value,
我们实例化的最后一个间隙 然后将其移位了大约负20
the last gap that we instantiated, and then shifted it by some negative 20
随机调整到20个像素 并确保它不会超过或超过--
to 20 pixels randomly, and made sure it didn't go above or beyond--
屏幕边缘上方或下方
above or below the edges of the screen.
回到管子对中 我们将继续 看一下第30行
Back in pipe pair, we're going to go ahead, and look at line 30.
对不起 实际上让我们更仔细地看看这里
I'm sorry, actually let's take a look a little bit more closely here
在第26行
at line 26.
所以上流社会就会变得自私自利
So upper gets top and self.y.
这就是差距所在 而精灵将在这个值上进行翻转
That's where the gap is, and the sprite is going to be flipped upon that value.
较低的价值将是这一点的转变
The lower value is going to be a shift of that.
因此 较低的精灵需要在顶部管道下方以缝隙的数量繁殖
So the lower sprite needs to spawn below the top pipe by the gap amount
所以这两个是自上而下的 但在那里
so that the two are top to bottom, but there
需要是他们两个之间的空间
needs to be that space between the two of them.
所以我们需要拿起那根管子 把它往下移 然后画下一根管子
So we need to take that pipe, shift it down, and then draw the next pipe.
所以我们取自 Y加上管子高度加上间隙高度
So we're going to take self.y plus pipe height plus gap height,
这会产生效果--记住 间隙高度是90像素
and that'll have the effect-- remember, gap height was 90 pixels.
管道高度是翻转y轴的结果
The pipe height is a result of flipping the y-axis,
不得不把它移到实际位置下
and having to shift it down the actual position.
所以如果我们回到第30行
So if we go back to line 30.
这是一个有趣的例子 说明了
This is an interesting illustration of what
当您在对表进行迭代时编辑表时发生
happens when you edit a table while you're iterating over a table,
我很快就会向你们详细展示这一点
and I'll show you this in detail shortly.
但基本上 在第30行 我们将一个名为Remove的标志设置为FALSE
But basically, on line 30, we're setting a flag called remove to false.
我们要做的是在我们摧毁这些物体之前
And what this is going to do is before we were just destroying the objects.
只要它越过屏幕的边缘 我们就把它毁了
Whenever it got past the edge of the screen, we just destroyed it.
但如果我们迭代一个值表
But if we're iterating over a table of values,
当您在大多数编程中执行删除操作时 让我们假设有一个管道对的表
let's say a table of pipe pairs, when you do a removal in most programming
语言--在Lua中 当您删除表值时 它没有索引
language-- in Lua, when you do a removal of a table value, and it's not indexed,
或者它是无键的 这意味着它是通过数字索引进行索引的
or it's non-keyed, which means that it's indexed by numerical indices,
这将使其他所有价值下降
this will shift every other value down.
所以当你迭代它的时候 你移动
And so when you're iterating it, and you shift
一切下跌 你目前正在操纵的价值
everything down, the value you are currently manipulating,
假设它等于1 如果去掉这个值
let's say it's equal to 1, if you remove that value,
将它以外的所有内容都向下移动1
you shift everything beyond it down by 1.
但然后你会递增到2
But then you're going to increment up to 2,
您跳过了以前只有2个 现在是1个
and you're skipping over what was previously just 2, and is now 1.
所以你实际上是跳过了你的一个条目
So you're effectively skipping over one of your entries,
而且它在很多情况下都有错误行为
and it has buggy behavior in a lot of scenarios.
在这种情况下 它会导致图形出现一点故障
In this case, it causes the graphics to glitch a little bit
因为它不在一帧上应用像素移位
because it doesn't apply a pixel shift on one frame,
因此 每当一根管子被移除--我实际上可以直观地展示这一点
and so whenever a pipe gets removed-- and I can actually show this visually,
移除该管道后留下的第一个管道
the first pipe left after that pipe gets removed
最后稍微向右移动了一点
ends up moving a little bit to the right,
所以你会看到奇怪的管子在每一帧中移动到鸟的左边
and so you get weird pipes shifting to the left of the bird on each frame.
因此 当您就地编辑表时 请制作
So whenever you edit a table in place, make
确保在迭代时不要删除它
sure not to delete while you're iterating over it.
这将会导致错误的行为
It's going to cause buggy behavior.
就像我说的 我很快就会向你们说明这一点
And like I said, I'll illustrate this for you very shortly.
在第36行 我们正在执行更新逻辑
On line 36, we are performing the update logic.
现在 管道对有两个管道 每个管道都有自己的渲染组件
Now, a pipe pair has two pipes, each with their own render components,
以及他们自己的立场
and their own positions.
我们使用之前为管道编写的代码
We're using the code that we wrote before for pipe,
我们将尝试在此基础上再做一点扩展
and we're going to try to expand upon it a little bit.
因此 我们仍然希望将大量代码推迟到管道类
So we still wanted to defer a lot of that code to the pipe class,
我们希望根据是否--更新管道--
and we want to update the pipes based on whether--
我们希望仍然跟踪他们自己的x 以及他们的渲染函数
We want to still keep track of their own x, and their render functions,
所以我们要看看 基本上 如果我们的烟斗对
and so we're going to see, basically, if our pipe pair
X大于负管道宽度 这与我们的逻辑完全相同
x is greater than negative pipe width, which is the same exact logic that we
以前用过的
were using before.
将我们自己的x设置为减去管道速度时间
Set our own x to that minus pipe speed times
三角洲时间 这与我们之前所做的操作相同
delta time, which is the same operation we were doing before.
但我们也在编辑我们自己的x 管道的下部和上部
But we are also editing the x of our self.pipes lower and upper,
这将允许我们--在第46行--
and this will allow us to-- on line 46--
像我们以前所做的那样渲染管道
render the pipes just as we were doing before
因为他们正在更新他们的x值 就像以前一样
because they're getting their x values updated just as they were before.
因此 我们实际上将渲染阶段推迟到管道
So we're effectively deferring the render phase to our pipes,
并且不需要在我们的代码中为此添加任何额外的逻辑
and not really needing to add any additional logic for that in our code.
我们也对pipe.lua进行了更改 所以我
We've made changes to pipe.lua as well, so I'm
往前走 在这里打开管道
going to go ahead, and open up pipe here.
我们在这里设置了它的高度和宽度作为内容
And we've set the height and width of it as contents here.
所以管道高度为288 然后发生了
So pipe height gets 288, and then happens
大小和屏幕差不多
to be about the size of the screen.
管道宽度达到70
Pipe width gets 70.
在31号 我们自己坐着 方向就是方向
On 31, we're sitting self.orientation gets orientation.
请注意我们的init函数 它之前刚刚
Notice our init function, which was previously just
为空 它不带参数 现在采用方向 并采用y值
empty, it took no parameters, now takes an orientation, and it takes a y value.
定向将允许我们问 基本上 我们的代码是
The orientation is going to allow us to ask, basically, is our code
上烟斗还是下烟斗？
a top or a bottom pipe?
如果它是顶管 我们需要翻转它 画出它 然后移动它
And if it's top pipe, we need to flip it, draw it, and shift it.
如果它是底部的管子 我们就把它画成正常的
If it's a bottom pipe, we're just going to draw it normal,
而不是表演任何花哨的精灵翻转或类似的东西
and not perform any sort of fancy sprite flipping or anything like that.
在渲染函数的下面是实际发生这种情况的地方
Down here in the render function is where this actually happens.
因此 在第39行 我们像往常一样绘制管道图像
So on line 39, we're drawing the pipe image as usual
在x处 但在y处 因为当你翻转一个精灵
at x, but at y, because when you flip a sprite
它最终完全翻转了y轴--它基本上是在它上面运行一面镜子
it ends up completely flipping the y-- it basically performs a mirror on it,
但不是在0 0
but it not at 0,0.
它基本上是按管道高度量向上移动
It basically shifts it up by pipe height amount.
我们需要跟踪这一点 并将其绘制为self.y加管道高度
We need to keep track of that, and draw it at self.y plus pipe height.
因为如果我们只画它自己 因为它是镜像的
Because if we draw it at just self.y, because it's going to be mirrored,
它会随着管道高度的变化而移动
and it's going to get shifted by pipe height amount,
它将超出屏幕的顶部边缘
it's going to be beyond the top edge of the screen.
我们需要解释这一点 解释这个事实
We need to account for that, account for the fact
我们在y轴上翻转它 然后把它拉下来
that we're flipping it on the y-axis, and bring it down.
观众：你翻转它的代码在哪里？
AUDIENCE: Where's the code where you flip it?
科尔顿·奥格登：问题是代码在哪里 我们把它翻到哪里去
COLTON OGDEN: The question is where is the code where we flip it.
这就是这条线上的实际情况
So that's actually here on this line.
在这种情况下 我们说如果自身方向等于顶部
On this condition, we're saying if self.orientation is equal to top,
那么我们想--
then we want to--
所以这里的参数 我将对此进行注释 只是为了澄清
so the parameters here, I'll comment this just for clarification.
观众：所以画图功能有翻转功能？
AUDIENCE: So the draw function has a flip function?
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 我在这里带你去看看
COLTON OGDEN: It does, I'll show you here.
所以在这个0中 我们添加了一些新参数
So this 0, we've added a few new parameters
致我们的love.graph ics.DrawFunction
to our love.graphics.drawfunction.
零表示旋转
Zero is rotation.
我们根本不会旋转它
We're not going to rotate it at all.
这是x轴上的比例
This is the scale on the x-axis.
所以x刻度 这是y轴上的刻度
So x scale, and this is the scale on the y-axis.
因此 如果我们应用1的比例运算 它是
So if we apply a scale operation of one, it's
这与根本不做规模是一样的
the same thing as doing no scale at all.
它会把它画在x轴上
It's going to draw it on the x-axis.
它只是会正常地画出来
It's just going draw it normally.
但如果是顶部 如果此管道已设置为顶部方向
But if it's top, if this pipe has been set to an orientation of top,
我们要将刻度设置为负1
we're going to set the scale to negative 1.
当你说精灵--
When you said a sprite--
将其比例因子设置为负1 则会有效地沿该轴翻转它
its scale factor to negative 1, it flips it along that axis, effectively.
这就是你得到镜像的方式
And so that's how you get mirroring.
大多数引擎允许您将缩放操作应用于2D纹理或2D
Most engines that allow you to apply scale operations to 2D textures or 2D
精灵 在轴上的负操作会将其镜像到该轴上
sprites, a negative operation on an axis will mirror it on that axis,
这就是我们在这里做的事情
and so that's what we're doing here.
因此 如果是顶管 我们会对其进行镜像
So we're mirroring it if it's a top pipe,
我们还改变了抽签地点
and we're also shifting its draw location
还有 因为当我们镜像它的时候 它会--
as well because when we mirror it, it's going to--
在0 0的时候 它会做同样的事情--它会
at 0,0 it's going to do the same-- it's going
基本上绘制完全相同的东西 但镜像在y轴上
to basically draw the same exact thing, but mirrored on the y-axis.
所以它需要--
So it's going to need--
如果我们想要在一个给定的位置画 翻转--
if we want to draw at a given location, flipped--
仍将其绘制为0 0 但将其翻转
still draw it at 0,0, but have it be flipped,
我们需要解释这种反转 并在有意义的情况下将其向下调整
we need to account for that flip, and shift it downwards if that makes sense.
因此 这基本上就是所有涉及到的事情
So that's essentially all that's involved there.
我认为这几乎就是所有的代码
And I think that's pretty much all of the code.
因此 我们现在有了正在被翻转的管道
So we have our pipes now that are being flipped.
如果它是顶管 它就会被拉移
If its a top pipe, it's going to get drawn shifted.
它将把另一根管子向下移动同样的量
It's going to have its other pipe shifted down by that amount,
它的y轴将增加间隙高度
and its y-axis is going to be increased by the gap height
所以它会被绘制成90个像素 无论您使用多少像素
so that it gets drawn 90 pixels, however many pixels you
想放在那根管子下面
want to set below that pipe.
因此 我们将进行演示
So we're going to go into demonstrate this.
现在转到50鸟 实际的repo和实际的发行版代码
Go up to fifty bird, the actual repo now, and the actual distro code.
我要到Bird6去 我要去跑步
I'm going to go into bird6, and I'm going to run it.
现在我们有了实际渲染的管道
And now we have pipes that are actually rendering.
但我们遗漏了几件重要的事情
But we're missing a couple of important things.
最重要的是 其中之一是我们现在还没有碰撞检测
Foremost, among them being that now we don't have collision detection yet.
所以我们可以无限地飞过这条航线
So we can just fly through this course infinitely,
但请注意 它们被移位了一个在负20之间的随机值
but notice that they're being shifted by a random value between negative 20
和20个像素
and 20 pixels.
它看起来或多或少像是为了某种目标而产生的
It looks more or less like it's being generated with some sort of goal
在脑海中
in mind.
这不是偶然的
It's not haphazard.
它不是到处都是 但你可以很容易地
It's not all over the place, but you could easily
想方设法调整这一点 也许差距高度是
find ways to tweak this such that maybe the gap height is
一些介于60和120之间的值
some value between 60 and 120.
所以你有容易的和困难的管子 或者你有--
And so you have easy and difficult pipes, or maybe you have--
我觉得我在屏幕下面太远了 我甚至都不能再站起来了
I think I'm so far below the screen that I can't even get back up anymore.
哦 好吧 这是个物理错误
Oh, OK, that's a physics error.
当你的价值达到某一点时 我认为这实际上就是它所做的
When your value gets to a certain point, I think that's actually what it's doing
它实际上是在溢出该值 并将其设置为负值
is it's actually overflowing the value, and setting it to a negative.
或下溢 并将其设置为负值
Or underflowing it, and setting it to a negative value,
然后递增 因为它变得太大了
and then incrementing it because it's gotten so large.
但你可以很容易地调整参数 如管道之间的宽度
But you could easily modulate parameters such as the width between the pipes
正如你在前面的图表中看到的 或者说高度
as you saw in the diagram before, or the height,
甚至是它们移动的速度 并发现
or even the speed at which they move, and find
调整它的方法 使游戏真正发挥作用 无论目标是什么
ways to tune it to make game play that actually works for whatever goal
你心里想的是--让它变得更容易或更难
you have in mind-- making it easier or more difficult.
这实际上是他们在那篇文章中谈到的一个话题
And that's actually a topic that they talked about in that article
我之前链接过的 在那里他们产生了级别
that I linked to before, where they generated levels
然后以编程方式对它们进行测试
programmatically, and then tested them programmatically
来确定是什么让Flappy Bird的等级变得困难或容易
to determine what makes level in Flappy Bird difficult or easy.
所以基本上 这些都是参数
And so basically, those are the parameters
当你在考虑程序生成时 你需要这样做
you need to way as you're thinking of procedural generation.
而程序性的生成 归根结底是公正的
And procedural generation, ultimately, is just
取你用来构建场景的值
taking values that you construct your scene with,
只是想方设法随意操控它们
and just finding ways to just manipulate them randomly.
数学 随机取一些值 简而言之 这就是你如何制造随机水平
Math.random some value, and that's how you make random levels in a nutshell.
制作好的随机水平是另一个问题
Making good random levels is another question.
观众：这家伙做得很少 赚了很多钱
AUDIENCE: This guy made a lot of money doing very little.
科尔顿·奥格登：他做到了 他做到了
COLTON OGDEN: He did, he did.
早在2013年 这款游戏就引发了很大的争议
There was a big controversy around this game back in 2013.
观众：他也有精神崩溃的症状 对吗？
AUDIENCE: He had like a nervous breakdown, too, right?
科尔顿·奥格登：我不知道我是否读得太多了
COLTON OGDEN: I don't know if I read too much into that,
但我做了一点研究 读到了一些
but I was doing a little bit of research, and was reading about some
那些东西
of that stuff.
我必须支持他 因为他寄希望于这一点
I've got to give him props for banking on that.
现在我们有了管子对
Now we have pipe pairs.
这可以说是该计划中最复杂的部分
That's arguably the most complex part of the program
因为现在向前看 当我们进入碰撞时
because going forward now, as we get into collision,
还有一些更多的概念 碰撞实际上是
and some more concepts, collision is actually something
我们上周谈到的 基本上都是一样的东西
that we touched on last week, and it's all basically the same stuff.
因此 如果我们进入Bird7 即我们应用程序的下一次迭代
So if we go into bird7, the next iteration of our application.
我要继续 打开主电源 卢亚
I'm going to go ahead, and open up main.lua,
然后我们要去74号线
and then we're going to go to line 74.
为了测试碰撞 我们还没有打分
And in order to test collision, we don't have scoring in place yet,
但我们需要一些方法来确定哦 我们撞上了一根管道
but we need some way to determine oh, we collided with a pipe.
我们需要一些反馈
We need some sort of feedback.
所以我们要做的是 我刚刚决定我们应该暂停比赛
So what we're going to do is I've just decided we should just pause the game.
所以一旦我们与管道相撞 我们就立即停下来
So once we collide with a pipe, let's just pause instantly
所以我们马上就知道 哦 我们撞到了一根管道
so we know immediately, oh, we collided with a pipe.
所以我将设置一个称为滚动的变量
So I'm going to set some variable called scrolling
在程序的顶部 从Main到True
at the top of the program in main to true.
我们在滚动
We're scrolling.
我们要开始滚动了 但当我
We're going to start scrolling, but when I
我不想再滚动了 当我想暂停游戏时
don't want to scroll any more, when I want to pause the game,
应将其设置为False
this should get set to false.
因此 在第120行 如果滚动 则执行所有这些更新逻辑
So on line 120, if scrolling, then do all of this update logic
就像我们以前做的那样
that we did before.
最后 我们重新设置了输入表
And then at the very end of that, we're resetting our input table.
因此我们仍然可以接受输入 但不能更新
So we can still take input, but no updates
如果将滚动设置为FALSE 则将发生
will take place if scrolling is set to false.
所有这些东西都在这个范围内 如果--
All of this stuff is within this if--
打扰一下 如果是滚动的话
excuse me, if scrolling, then.
非常简单
So very simple.
我们只需将其封装在某个变量中
We'll just encapsulate it all within some variable
我们可以打开和关闭
that we can turn on and off.
然后在152上 在该代码块内
And then on 152, within that chunk of code
它包含在If条件中
that is being contained within that if condition,
我们只是在做一个非常简单的迭代
we're just doing a very simple iteration.
每一根管子 这应该是L成对的--
For each pipe, this should be for l pair in pairs of--
哦 不 对不起
oh no, sorry.
对于成对的每根管子--
For every pipe in the pairs of--
在本例中 它是一个嵌套的for循环
it's a nested for loop in this case.
所以基本上 在检查每一对的循环中 为了更新它
So basically, within the loop that looks over every single pair, to update it,
我们正在做另一个循环 循环通过这对管道
we're doing another loop that's looping through with the pipes in that pair.
因此 它只是一个上下管道两次迭代的循环
So it's only a loop of two iterations with the upper and the lower pipe.
我们也可以说 如果鸟撞上了上面--
We could just also say if bird collides with upper--
基本上 如果是上半身或下半身 或者是下半身
basically, if pair.upper or pair.lower, or pair.pipes
往上走 往下走 往下走 但这个干净多了
to upper pair.pipes.lower, but this is a little cleaner.
它的可扩展性更强
It's more scalable.
我们可以增加更多的管道 如果我们想的话 即使这不会发生
We can add more pipes if we want to, even though it wouldn't happen.
但是对于每一个配对的管道 我们在这里有一个函数 我们
But for every pipe in pair.pipes, we have a function here that we
还没有定义为鸟：碰撞
haven't defined yet called bird:collides.
所以 如果鸟撞上了管子 它就会吸进管子
So if bird collides pipe-- so it takes in a pipe.
所以它将返回一个真或假的值 我们知道--
So it's going to return a true or false value, we know that--
将滚动设置为FALSE
set scrolling to false.
所以我们发生冲突 滚动设置为假 更新逻辑
So we collide, scrolling set to false, update logic
将被完全关闭
is going to get shut off completely.
所以我们会暂停游戏的效果
So we're going to have the effect of pausing the game.
我们现在要进入小鸟 卢亚
We're going to go into bird.lua right now,
我们将看看我们是如何实现这一点的
and we're going to actually see how we implement this,
它看起来会和我们上周所做的非常相似
and it's going look very familiar to what we did last week.
所以在Bird.Lua中 这个函数从29减到45
So in bird.lua, this function here, from 29 down to 45,
这只是我们上周做的AABB碰撞检测测试
it's just an aabb collision detection test that we did last week.
我们只是在检查以确保任何边缘--
We're just checking to make sure any edges are--
右边缘 确保它在左边
right edge, make sure that is to the left
第二个框的右边缘
of the right edge of the second box.
第一个盒子的底边应该是--
Bottom edge of box one should be--
框1的底边或底边应在底边或顶边之上
or bottom edge of box one should be above bottom edge or top
第二个盒子的边缘
edge of box two.
如果所有这些都成立 则返回TRUE
If all of these things hold true, then return true.
否则 返回FALSE
Else, return false.
这意味着我们发生了碰撞
That means we have a collision.
注意 我把这里的所有东西都移了几个常量值
And notice that I've shifted everything here by a couple of constant values.
有没有人本能地知道我为什么
Does anybody have any instinct as to why I'm
说的是self.x加2 而不是self.x self.wide减4？
saying self.x plus 2 instead of just self.x self.width minus 4?
为什么我们要检查这种情况下鸟的偏移量
Why we're checking for that offset for the bird in this case
当它与管子相比时
when it is compared with the pipe.
观众：它是鸟的一半大小吗？
AUDIENCE: It's half the size of the bird?
科尔顿·奥格登：这还不到一半
COLTON OGDEN: It's not quite half.
它比以前小了几个像素
It's a few pixels smaller.
我们知道为什么要这么做吗？
Do we know why we want to do this?
我们基本上是在缩小盒子
We're basically shrinking the box.
我们为什么要缩小盒子？
Why would we want to shrink the box?
观众：实际的画作之间有差距
AUDIENCE: There's a gap between the actual drawing [INAUDIBLE]
科尔顿·奥格登：所以不完全是
COLTON OGDEN: So not quite.
因此 这幅图之间并没有实际的差距
So there isn't an actual gap between the drawing.
这更多的是一个问题 我们想在多大程度上挫败我们的用户
It's more a question of how much we want to frustrate our users.
如果我们的像素完美地与管道相撞 就不会有取舍
If we're pixel perfect colliding with the pipes, there's no give and take.
就像你们相撞了 即使--它甚至可能
It's like you collide, and even if-- it might even
看起来就像你甚至没有撞到管道
look as if you're not even colliding with the pipe,
而你仍然会遇到碰撞
and you're still getting a collision.
你的用户在想 好吧 这不公平
Your users are thinking, well, that's not fair.
这真的很苛刻
That's really harsh.
我们正在缩小盒子 这样即使它们只差一个像素
We're shrinking our box so that even if they're just a pixel off,
他们仍然会有一点回旋余地
they'll still get a little bit of leeway,
在碰撞方面 它会稍微放松一些
and it'll be a little bit less strict in terms of the collision,
这在游戏中是很常见的事情 当你的角色具有精灵
and this is a very common thing in games when you have characters whose sprites
不一定会填满你为他们分配的整个盒子
may not necessarily fill the entire box that you've allocated for them,
即使你在做长方体碰撞
even though you're doing box collision.
只要给你的用户几个像素深度 不管多少
Just give your users a couple of pixels deep, however many
你想要的 它们可以与任何东西重叠
you want, and they can overlap with whatever
它们只是在它实际撞击之前的一小部分
they're colliding with just a tiny bit before it actually
在碰撞中触发真 这会让你的游戏感觉更宽容
triggers a true on the collision, and it makes your game feel more forgiving,
然后也因此而更有趣
and then also more fun as a result of that.
这就是为什么我们有--
So that's why we have--
我们不是直接在盒子的x0上测试 而是测试x+2
instead of testing directly on x0 of that box, we're testing x plus 2,
然后是自身宽度减去4 因为当我们移动时
and then self.width minus 4 because when we shift,
我们将宽度加到正2值上 我们需要负4
we add width to a plus 2 value, we need minus 4
所以我们从右边得到2 而且是一样的
so that we get 2 off the right edge, and same thing
表示高度和y值
goes for the height, and the y value.
因此 这只执行AABB冲突检测
And so this just performs aabb collision detection.
需要管道 这意味着我们需要确保
Expects a pipe, which means that we need to ensure
管子有一个x和一个y 一个宽度和一个高度 它确实有
that the pipe has an x and a y, a width and a height, which it does.
实际上 这里只是一个常量
Actually, just a constant here.
我们只是在检查管道的宽度和高度
We're just checking pipe width and pipe height.
我们可能不该这么做
We probably shouldn't do that.
在这种情况下 它应该是pipe.width pipe.height
It should be pipe.width, pipe.height in that case,
因为这样一来 这不可能只是一根管子
because then this couldn't necessarily just be a pipe.
它可以是场景中具有XY、宽度和高度的任何对象
It could be anything in our scene that has a xy, a width, and a height.
这可能是一起一般用途的碰撞
It could be a general purpose collision.
事实上 如果你愿意 你也可以做的是
And actually, something you could also do if you wanted to is
只需编写一个名为Collides的函数 该函数接受两个内容
just write a function called collides that takes in two things
你知道它有包围盒 而且会
that you know have bounding boxes, and will
允许您对任何对象执行碰撞检测
allow you to perform collision detection on anything
在场景中的任意两个实体之间
in your scene between any two entities.
我想 这将是一种更具伸缩性的方式
That would be a more scalable way, I guess,
处理它 而不是一定要拥有它
of dealing with it, rather than necessarily having it
明确定义为鸟类和管子是对撞机
specifically defined as birds and pipes being the colliders.
但在这种情况下 这是我们唯一真正
But in this case, this is the only thing we're really
除了地面以外 都与之相撞
colliding with, except for the ground.
但当你与地面相撞时 你需要做的就是
But when you collide with the ground, all you need to do
就是看看你的y体位加上你的身高
is just check to see whether your y position plus your height
已经到了屏幕边缘以下
has gone below the edge of the screen.
那么 对于如何做到这一点 有什么问题吗？
So any questions as to how that?
观众：为什么你要加2n再减4 而不是只减2？
AUDIENCE: Why did you add 2n and subtract 4 instead of just subtract 2?
科尔顿·奥格登：所以问题是为什么我们要加2减去
COLTON OGDEN: So the question was why did we add 2 and subtract
4而不是减去2？
4 instead of just subtract 2?
因为当你添加一个--
Because when you add a--
因为我们做的是self.x+2 基本上我们是
because we're doing self.x plus 2, basically we're
移动整个盒子 基本上 在这里 在这一部分
shifting the whole box, essentially, here in this part.
所以 self.x加2带来了盒子的开始
So self.x plus 2 brings the beginning of the box
我们与右侧的2个像素相撞
that we're colliding with 2 pixels to the right.
但如果我们只做2个像素减去2 那么盒子的右边缘
But if we just do 2 pixels minus 2, then the box's right edge
仍然是框的右边缘
is still the right edge of the box.
我们希望它向内移动2个像素
We want it to be shifted inwards by 2 pixels.
因为我们在方框的开始处移动了x位置 2个像素以上
Because we've shifted at the start of our box, the x position, 2 pixels over,
我们需要将它向内移动4个像素 因为
we need to shift it 4 pixels inwards because that
会产生这样的效果 我们的长方体在右边缘有2个像素
will have the effect of our box being 2 pixels into the right edge.
这说得通吗？
Does that make sense?
好的 我想这就是Bird7的全部内容
OK, so I think that's everything for bird7.
我们将继续 现在运行Bird7
We're going to go ahead, and run bird7 now.
记住 如果我们碰到管道 我们应该立即暂停
And recall, if we hit a pipe, we should instantly pause.
如此跳跃 跳跃 跳跃
So bouncing, bouncing, bouncing.
我要在这里通过一对管道
I'm going to go through one pair of pipes here,
然后我会故意打这个
and then I'm going to hit this one on purpose.
哦 我们停顿了一下
Oh, we paused.
请注意 我们有一点回旋余地
And notice that we had a little bit of leeway.
我们在那里有几个像素--以防万一
We got a couple of pixels there just to give us-- in case we
意外的--而且 它还考虑到了你可能会移动
accidentally-- and also, it takes into consideration you could move,
因为你的速度 几个像素
because of your velocity, a couple of pixels
超越了你所碰撞的东西的严格的硬边缘
beyond necessarily the strict hard edge of what you're colliding with
基于通过的帧的数量
based on how many frames of passed.
基本上 你的速度是多少 你的位置是什么
Basically, essentially what your velocity is, and what your position is.
在这种情况下 我认为看起来我们实际上
In this case, I think it looks like we're actually
边缘上方三四个像素 因为我们的速度是
three or four pixels above the edge because our velocity was
这么高是因为我们跳了 但它一检测到碰撞 就像
so high because we jumped, but as soon as it detected the collision, as
我们一到那个画面上 我们的位置就是这样
soon as we were on that frame where our position was such
我们确实触发了碰撞检测的True
that we did trigger true for our collision detection,
它暂停了游戏
it paused the game.
循环设置为FALSE
Looping was set to false.
我们不再运行任何更新逻辑 这是我们的基本方式
We no longer ran any update logic, and this is our basic way
得到关于这方面的反馈
of getting feedback about that.
然而 它并不是特别有说服力 游戏智慧
However, it's not particularly compelling, gameplay wise,
所以我们想要进入得分领域
and so we want to get into scoring.
在我们开始得分之前 也是与之相关的
Before we get to scoring though, and also associated with that,
我们比赛的不同状态
different states of our game.
因此 如果我们开始得分 显然我们想要
So if we get into scoring, clearly we want
有一个屏幕告诉我们什么时候输了 我们的比分是多少
to have a screen that tells us when we lost, and what our score was.
我们可能还应该有一个标题屏幕
We should also probably have a title screen
因为我们才刚刚进入游戏阶段
because we're just jumping right into the gameplay.
我们想要一个可以让我们玩完游戏的屏幕
We want a screen that lets us play through the game,
正如我们将在稍后看到的 一个屏幕也为我们提供了
and as we'll see in a little bit, a screen that also gives us
有时间 一旦我们开始比赛 开始倒计时
some time, once we start the game, to count down.
就像是说 哦 三 二 一 去 而不仅仅是哦
Sort of say, oh, three, two, one, go, rather than just oh,
去吧 哦 我不知道我在做什么
go, and oh, I don't know what I'm doing.
我大惑不解
I'm bewildered.
所以这是一张对国家进行建模的图表
So this is a diagram that sort of models the state
我们将在我们的程序中使用的流 我们的游戏
flow that we're going to be using in our program here, our game.
我们将假设我们从某种标题屏幕状态开始
We're going to assume that we start on some sort of title screen state.
所以从左到右
So going left to right.
标题屏幕状态将转换到倒计时状态
A title screen state will transition to the count down state,
然后 我们可以随心所欲地定义这些转变
and then we can define, however we want, those transitions to be.
在这种情况下 假设我们按Enter键
In this case, let's just say we press Enter.
标题屏幕状态进入倒计时状态
The title screen state goes to countdown state.
一旦倒计时状态--
Once countdown state has--
一旦为此触发了转换 我们就应该进入播放状态
once the transition has triggered for that, we should go to the play state.
然后一旦转换触发到播放状态
And then once the transition triggers for play state,
我们将进入得分状态
we're going to go down to the score state.
然后得分状态应该回到倒计时状态 这个模型
And then score state should go back into countdown state, and this models
我们整个应用程序的流程--
our entire application's flow--
从上到下 从左到右 按时间顺序
top to bottom, left to right, chronologically.
因此 让我们继续 看看一些代码
So let's go ahead, and take a look at some code
关于我们将如何实现这一点
as to how we're going to accomplish this.
上周 我提到了我们--实际上在早些时候的演讲中--我们
Last week, I alluded to taking us-- and actually earlier in lecture, us
从这种基于字符串的方法 到使用if跟踪我们的状态
going from this string based approach, to keeping track of our state with if
条件 到基于类的方法 这就是
conditions, to a class based approach, and that's
我们今天要说明的是
what we're going to illustrate today.
所以我要继续 打开Bird8
So I'm going to go ahead, and open up bird8.
在Bird8中 我将继续 从Main开始
And in bird8, I'm going to go ahead, and start with main.
在Main中 在第36行 我们正在获取一个名为状态机的新类
So in main, on line 36, we're acquiring a new class called state machine,
以及我们正在定义的其他几个类 称为Bay State Play
and a few other classes that we're defining called bay state, play
状态和标题屏幕状态
state, and title screen state.
这些是我们的状态机的组成部分
And these are the components of our state machine,
现在 它们不再仅仅是我们更新函数中的代码块
and they've now, instead of being just blocks of code in our update function,
它们是独立的块、独立的模块
they're separate blocks, separate modules that
有自己的逻辑 自己的更新和渲染逻辑
have their own logic, their own update and render logic,
我们很快就会看到这一点
and we'll see that very shortly.
在78号线 如果我们往下走--
On line 78, if we go down here--
除此之外 我还实例化了一些字体
separate from that, I'm also instantiating a bunch of fonts.
我们上个星期就做过了
We did this last week.
所以 love.graph ics.newfont接受一个字体文件 然后是一个大小
So love.graphics.newfont takes in a font file and then a size.
我在这里创建了几种不同的字体 因为我们有几种不同的方式
I've created a few different fonts here because we have a few different ways
向用户提供反馈
of giving feedback to the user.
我们想要一个小字体来显示按Enter键
We want a small font for displaying press Enter
作为一个开始 或者类似的东西
to a start, or something like that.
我们想要一个中等字体来显示游戏的名称 也许
We want a medium font to display the name of the game, perhaps.
或者 我认为实际上 Flappy Font应该对此负责
Or, I think actually, Flappy Font is responsible for that.
中等字体 我想 是为了得分
Medium font, I think, was for score.
巨大的字体为我们的倒计时
Huge font for our countdown.
我们想要一个大字体 正好在屏幕中央
We want a big font right in the middle of screen
三 二 一 然后我们开始
that says three, two, one, and then we start.
然后我们将首先将其设置为Flappy Font 它
And then we're just going to start off by setting it to Flappy Font, which
将成为我们的标题字体
is going to be our title font.
所以没有什么真正的新东西 但可以说是我们的用户界面的开始
So nothing really new, but the beginning of our UI, so to speak.
在第92行 这是新的 实际上这是
On line 92, this is new, and actually this
是一种命名约定的演示
is a demonstration of a type of naming convention
您将经常在游戏代码库中看到
you'll see often in game code bases.
我们还没有使用它 但我们将在未来开始使用它
We haven't used it yet, but we will start using it in the future.
我们在全局变量前面加上一个小写的g
We prefix a global variable with a lower case g.
这可以让您知道当您正在挖掘一系列文件时
This lets you know when you're digging through a bunch of files
那个哦 这是一个全局变量
that oh, this is a global variable.
好的 所以我应该知道它可能没有在这个模块中定义
OK, so I should probably know it's probably not defined in this module.
也许是这样 但我知道这是全球性的
Maybe it is, but I know it's global.
您可能会看到的其他内容是小写
Other things you might see are lower case
M代表成员 这意味着这是一个成员函数 或者是一个类的字段
m for member, which means that this is a member function, or a field of a class,
你可以一目了然 知道
and you can instantly see at a glance, and know
好的 如果我想找出这个的定义
OK, if I want to find the definition for this,
它看起来像是一个成员函数
it looks like it's a member function.
所以它可能就在这个班级里 在这里的某条线上
So it's probably in this class, here at some line.
你很容易就能找到
You can easily find it.
因此 在未来的课程中 我们将使用
And so in future lectures, we'll be using
更多的是这个小写的g 表示全局变量 我们一个模块一个模块地使用
more of this lowercase g for global variables that we use module to module.
在本例中 我们实例化了一个状态机
In this case, we're instantiating a StateMachine.
所以我们使用的是这个类 我们稍后会看一下
So we're using the class that we will take a look at in a second.
StateMachine接收一个带有键的表
The StateMachine takes in a table with keys
映射到将返回我们的状态的函数
that map to functions that will return our states.
所以我们可以只调用更改一些值 它将在我们的状态机中
So we can just call change some value, and it'll have in our state machine,
它基本上会在这里引用该表中键
it will basically reference that key in this table here,
它将根据--它将调用该函数
and it'll call that function based on-- it'll
基本上将该StateMachine的当前状态设置为任何状态
basically set the current state of that StateMachine to whatever state
由该键处的函数返回
gets returned by the function at that key.
因此 在本例中 更改将触发返回新标题屏幕状态
So in this case, change is going to trigger return new TitleScreenState,
我们将得到--状态机是
and we're going to get-- the StateMachine is
将设置为标题屏幕 有效地
going to be set to the title screen, effectively,
我们马上来看看标题屏幕是什么样子的
and we'll take a look at what the title screen looks like momentarily.
在第96行 是的 我们将切换到标题屏幕
On line 96, yeah, we're changing to title screen.
在第134行 请注意我们实际上没有太多更新
On line 134, notice that we don't really have much update
这个应用程序中再也没有逻辑了
logic in this application anymore.
我们仍在更新卷轴 因为这是
We're still updating the scrolls because this is
我们所有州都想要的行为
behavior we want across all our states.
无论我们处于什么状态 我们都要确保
No matter what state we're in, we want to make sure
我们的背景和我们的地面滚动 所以我们有运动
that our background and our ground scroll so that we have movement.
我们不需要将此行为状态复制到状态
We don't need to duplicate this behavior state to state.
这是我们游戏的一个全球性特征
This is a global feature of our game.
所以我们只是像以前一样在这里跟踪它
So we're just keeping track of it here just as we would before,
但我们游戏中任何其他需要更新的内容
but anything else in our game that need to be updated
现在可以推迟到我们的StateMachine类
can now be deferred to our StateMachine class.
当我们调用gStateMachine更新增量时间时
And when we call gStateMachine update delta time,
它将会看看我们目前的状态是什么
it's going to look and see what's our current state,
它将更新这种状态
and it's going to update that state.
基本上就是那一大块 如果这块
And that's going to basically be that chunk, that if chunk
按照我们上个星期做的逻辑来做
do this logic that we were doing from before last week when
我们有一个更原始的状态机
we had a more primitive StateMachine.
第46行 一模一样
Line 46, same exact thing.
在背景和地面之间 因为它们将始终渲染场景
Between the background and the ground, because those will always render scene
要设置场景 我们希望呈现当前的活动状态
to scene, we want to render our current active state
使用我们的状态机渲染功能
using our StateMachine render function.
因此 让我们继续下去 简单地看看我们的状态机程序库
And so let's go ahead, and just look briefly at our state machine library.
这是一个非常简单的代码
It's a very simple code.
它实际上取自我在课程前面提到的那本书--
It's actually taken from the book I alluded to earlier in the lecture--
如何制作RPG
How to Make an RPG.
他们给了你这个状态机 我认为这真的很干净
They give you this state machine, which really cleanly, I think,
处理状态转换
handles state transition.
基本上 它需要一个初始化 然后是一系列的状态
Basically, it takes an init, and then a series of states.
它有一个空类或空表
It has an empty class, or empty table.
所以所有这些都是空的
So all of these are just empty.
如果没有--这是你可以做的事情
If there is no-- this is a thing you can do
在Lua中 它只允许您在变量不是
in Lua, which just lets you initialize a variable if it's not
在您的函数中给定值
given a value in your function.
因此 self.States获得州或某个值
So self.states gets states or some value.
这意味着如果州等于假值 则等于零
Which means that if states is equal to a false value, it's equal to nothing,
把它放到这张空桌子上
just set it to this empty table.
所以这只是一种速记 而不是说如果国家等于零
So it's just a shorthand for instead of saying if states equals nothing,
然后将STATES设置为空表
then set states to empty table.
Self.Current只是一个空类或空状态
Self.current is just an empty class or empty state.
所以这基本上就是一个国家 它只是一套方法--
So this is basically what a state is, it's just a set of methods--
渲染、更新、进入和退出功能
a render, update, enter, and exit function.
这是一种状态 然后你定义所有的行为
That's a state, and then you define all of the behavior
在这些函数中的每一个中 这或多或少地编译了您的状态
in each of these functions, and that compiles your state more or less.
我们的Change函数接受一个名称 然后还有一些可选参数
Our change function takes in a name, and then also some optional parameters
我们可以用来进入那种状态
that we can use to enter that state.
当我们改变状态时 或者调用任何状态的退出函数时
When we change the state, or call the exit function of whatever state
我们进去了
we're in.
所以 退出这个状态吧
So exit that state.
也许您的函数需要您释放一些内存
Maybe your function needs you to de-allocate some memory.
将电流设置为等于取那个名字
Set the current equal to taking that name,
然后调用那里的任何函数
and then call whatever functions there.
所以它会回来的
So it's going to return.
在这种情况下 我们前面已经看到 它将返回一个新的标题屏幕状态
In that case, we saw earlier, it's going to return a new title screen state.
所以这就是现在的情况
So that's going to be what current is.
有了self.Current 我们将进入该状态机
With self.current, we're going to then enter that state machine.
因此 我们将调用在那里定义的Enter函数
So we're going to call the Enter function that we defined there
使用我们传递给Change的任何输入参数 这些参数都是可选的
with whatever enter parameters we pass into change, which are optional.
然后在这里 StateMachineUpdate只更新当前状态
And then here, StateMachineUpdate just updates whatever the current state is,
并且无论当前状态是什么 都会进行渲染更新
and render updates whatever the current state is as well.
所以我要开始稍微快一点
And so I'm going to start going a little bit quickly
就因为我们的时间不多了
just because we're running short on time.
BaseState 它所做的只是实现空方法
BaseState, all it does is just implements empty methods
这样你就可以继承这个状态 而你
so that you can just inherit this state, and you
可以选择要定义的方法
can choose which methods you want to define
不会抛出任何错误 因为它会盲目地调用所有这些函数
without throwing any errors because it blindly will call all these functions,
没有检查它们是否真正得到了实施
not checking to see whether they're actually implemented.
所以这是一种让你快速避免
And so this is a way for you to just quickly avoid
从本质上讲 是大量的样板代码
a lot of boilerplate code, essentially.
这里的标题屏幕状态 这是您处理类库的方式
The TitleScreenState here, this is your way of with the class library,
只包括属于BaseState的所有东西
just including everything that belongs to BaseState.
所以继承 如果你熟悉其他语言
So inheriting, if you're familiar with other languages
使用继承--获取一个对象 复制
that use inheritance-- take an object, copy
把那个物体或那个类的所有东西都放到这个里面
everything from that object or that class, put it into this one,
然后再加入新的东西
and then add new stuff to it.
这基本上就是继承的含义
That's basically what inheritance is.
我们继承了BaseState 因此它具有BaseState的所有功能
We're inheriting from BaseState so it has all the functions BaseState has,
最重要的是 我们定义了一个更新函数
and then on top of that, we're defining an update function.
因此 如果我们按Enter或Return 则更改全局状态机
So if we press Enter or Return, change the global state machine
转到播放状态
to the play state.
然后对于渲染 我们将渲染50只鸟
And then for the render, we're just going to render fifty bird,
然后在屏幕中间按Enter键
and press Enter halfway in the middle of the screen.
然后是PlayState 基本上是对一些人来说--
And then the PlayState, essentially to some--
基本上 PlayState是我们之前运行的所有代码 只是
basically, what the PlayState is is all of the code that we ran before, only
现在我们只是把它放在这里的更新函数中
now we're just putting it in the update function here,
和这里的渲染功能 以及制作鸟、管子对、计时器
and the render function here, and making bird, pipe pairs, timer,
和此状态对象的最新成员字段
and lastY member fields of this state object.
因此 我们将继续 并且运行得非常快
So we'll go ahead, and run this really fast.
这是我们的标题屏幕状态
This is our title screen state.
因此 在开始时 我们将更改为标题屏幕状态
So at the very beginning, we change to title screen state.
它所做的就是渲染 然后是滚动行为
All it does is render, and then the scrolling behavior
遍及所有班级 所有州
is throughout all classes, all states.
无论如何 我们都会看到这一点
So we'll see that no matter what.
一旦您按下Enter 它就会触发更改
Once you press Enter, it'll trigger change
播放 这将返回播放状态 然后
to play, which will return a play state, and then
现在我们又回到了以前的地方 我们现在看到了不同之处
now we're back where we were before, and we're seeing the difference now
有几个不同的州
in having a couple of different states.
所以快点 我来看一下比分更新
So quickly, I'll go through the score update.
所以这比上一个例子稍微复杂一些
So this is a little bit more complicated than the last example.
但总而言之 在鸟身上--
But to summarize, in bird--
对不起 我们坐的是Bird9
sorry, we're in bird9.
所以在Bird9中 如果我们去这里 我们将去Main
So in bird9, if we go here, we're going to go to main.
请注意 在Main中 下面是我们定义StateMachine的地方
So notice that in main, down where we define our StateMachine,
我们将继续进行 还要注意我们需要一个新的分数
we're going to go ahead, and also note that we require a new score
状态 因为现在我们想要显示分数屏幕
state because now we want to display a score screen.
在第96行 Score获得一个函数 我们在该函数中返回一个Score状态对象
Down on line 96, score gets a function where we return a score state object.
所以现在我们可以更改为得分 它将返回到那个状态
So now we can change to score, and it will return that state,
我们可以定义ScoreState中的所有行为
and we can define all the behavior within ScoreState
我们需要显示一个分数
that we need to display a score.
在PipePair中 我们有一个名为self.core的新变量
In PipePair, we have a new variable called self.scored.
将其设置为True或False
Set it to true or false.
我们要把它设置为真 如果鸟有
We're going to set it to true if the bird has
穿过了这对管子的右边缘
gone past the right edge of the pair of pipes.
这将使我们有效地得到一分
That will have the effect of us scoring a point, effectively,
因为我们要做的就是确保鸟儿们
because all we need to do is just make sure the birds got
穿过那对管子 否则它
past that pair of pipes because otherwise it
都会与之相撞
will have collided with it.
如果超过了它 将其设置为True 然后在我们的分数上增加一分
If it does go past it, set it to true, and then add a point to our score.
在我们的游戏状态下 我们可以看到我们已经添加了一分
And in our play state, we can see that we've added a point.
所以如果我们进入我们的播放状态 26是我们实际
So if we go to our play state, 26 is where we actually
记录我们的分数
keep track of our score.
在我们的游戏状态下 Self.Score得0分
Self.score gets 0 in our play state.
我们要继续往前走 一直走到第56行
We're going to go ahead, and go down to line 56.
因此 对于每一双 如果还没有得分--
So for every pair, if it's not been scored yet--
因为如果已经打分了 我们就不需要计算了
because we don't need to calculate this if it's already been scored.
一旦得分 我们就应该忽略它的得分
We should ignore it in terms of scoring once it's been scored.
如果x加宽度小于我们的Bird.x
If the x plus width is less than our bird.x,
这意味着我们的鸟在这对管子的右边
meaning our bird is beyond the right edge of the pair of pipes,
增加我们的分数 并将该对设置为真
increment our score, and set that pair to true.
然后我们会因为这个情况 然后忽略它
We will then thereafter, because of this condition, ignore it,
我们还将增加我们的分数
and we're also going to increment our score.
因此 它将被记录下来
So it's going to be kept track of.
在83号公路上 请注意 如果我们与管道相撞
On 83, notice that if we're colliding with a pipe,
我们现在应该转换到我们的得分状态
we should transition to our score state now.
我们也会传入自己的分数 分数作为表格
And we're also passing in score gets self.score as a table
因为请记住 我们可以在调用Change时传入参数
because remember, we can pass in parameters when we call change,
这将被传递到我们州的Enter函数中
and this will be passed into our enter function in our state,
然后分数就等于自己
and then score is going to equal self.score.
我们将有权访问该分数状态内的分数
We'll have access to the score within that score state.
我们不必把它作为一个全局变量来跟踪
We don't have to keep track of it as a global variable
在这两个地方都能看到
to see it in both locations.
在93号公路上 同样的事情
And on 93, the same exact thing.
这是碰撞 以检查我们是否与屏幕底部发生碰撞
This is collision to check whether we've collided with the bottom of the screen.
如果我们的y大于虚拟高度减去15 做完全相同的事情
If our y is greater than virtual height minus 15, do the exact same thing.
转换到分数状态 并在当前分数中传递它
Transition to the score state, and pass it in our current score.
所以另一个死亡条件
So another death condition.
然后104 我们要设置Flappy Font
And then 104, we're just going to set Flappy Font,
然后我们将把我们的分数呈现在屏幕左上角的8 8
and then we're going to render our score at the top left of the screen at 8,8,
这将会产生这种效果
and that will have that effect.
最后 在这里 我们的分数状态非常简单
And so lastly, here, our scores state is pretty simple.
我们要做的就是--从我们传入的参数中
All it is is we're going to get-- from those parameters we passed in
更改后 self.core等于pars.core
by a change, self.score equals params.score.
我们要 当我们按回车键的时候 回到游戏中
We're going to, when we press Enter, go back to play,
然后我们将呈现“You Lost” 然后是分数
and then we're going to render 'you lost', and the score,
我们可以访问它--self.core 然后按Enter键再次播放
which we have access to-- self.score, and then press Enter to play again,
在此过程中更改字体
changing fonts along the way.
因此 如果我们回到Bird9 我们运行这个
And so if we go back to bird9, and we run this,
请注意 现在我们在左上角有一个分数
notice that now we have a score in the top left.
我只得一分 然后就死定了
And I'm going to get one point, and then die.
然后我们现在进入计分屏幕
Then we go to our score screen now.
记住 我们从我们的Play状态向它传递了分数
Remember, we passed score into it from our play state.
我们将其作为参数传递 然后我们
We passed it in as parameters, and then we
可以再次按回车键 返回播放状态 当我们倒地时
can press Enter again, go back to play state, and when we fall to the ground,
我们也是这么做的
we do it as well.
我们刚刚看了一下如何在我们的比赛中增加得分
So we've just taken a look at how to add scoring to our game,
但是 如果我们想要添加一个倒计时屏幕呢？
but what if we want to add a count down screen?
也许我们希望在实际比赛之前提示用户三、二、一
Maybe we want the users to be prompted three, two, one before the actual game
开始向他们扔烟斗
starts throwing pipes at them.
给他们时间让他们适应环境
Give them the time to sort of get acclimated.
我们将继续下去 看看如何
We're going to go ahead, and take a look at how
我们可以使用与上一个示例非常类似的另一个状态来完成此操作
we might do this using another state very similar to the last example.
我们将添加一个名为Countdown State的新州
We're going to add a new state called CountdownState,
它显示在这里的第38行
which is shown here on line 38.
我们还将在我们的状态机中
We're also going to, down in our state machine,
添加一个新的键 它返回一个新的倒计时状态 就像以前一样
add a new key, which returns one of the new countdown states, just as before,
然后我们将继续 看看我们的实际倒计时
and then we're going to go ahead, and take a look at our actual countdown
请在此说明
state here.
因此 在我们的Countdown State.Lua中 与其他文件夹一样 它位于我们的States文件夹中
So in our CountdownState.lua, which is in our states folder, as the others,
它继承自BaseState
it inherits from BaseState.
我们已经将倒计时时间初始设置为0.75
We have initialized a countdown time to 0.75.
这一次是在几秒钟内
This time in seconds.
一秒太长了 所以我把它改成了0.75秒
One second is a little long, so I made it 0.75 seconds.
我们将把计数初始化为3 将计时器初始化为0
We're going to initialize a count to three, and a timer to 0.
点票就要开始了
The count's going to start.
一旦倒计时过去 它就会使用计时器
It's going to use a timer once the countdown time has elapsed,
就在这里 正如这个逻辑所示
right here, as this logic shows.
一旦计时器超过倒计时时间 就增加计时器
Increase the timer once the timer has gone past countdown time.
我们想要继续 并将其设置为--
We want to go ahead, and set it to--
我们要通过倒计时来取模
we're going to modulo by countdown time.
所以循环返回到0加上超过倒计时时间的任何值
So loop it back to 0 plus whatever amount beyond the countdown time
我们去了 这样我们就能顺畅地追踪时间
we went so that we have a smooth track of time.
我们将自己设定 计数减去它自己
We're going to set self.count minus itself
乘以1 我们就是3 2 1
by 1 so that we go three, two, one.
如果我们的计数是0 这意味着我们已经
And then if our count is 0, which means that we've
在我们的统计中一路下降 我们是
gone all the way down in our count, we're
继续使用我们的状态机 并更改为Play状态
going to go ahead and use our state machine, and change to the play state.
在这里 我们将字体设置为我们设置的字体--
And here, we're setting our font to a font that we've set--
HugeFont--然后我们就是两条线了
hugeFont-- and then we're just twostring,
一个接受字符串或数字的小函数
a little function that takes a string, or takes a number,
转换为字符串
converts to a string.
我们在显示自己 数到0,120 然后我们的.
We're displaying self.count at 0, 120, and then our--
它是print tf
it's printf.
所以我们基本上从0开始 y 120 虚拟宽度对齐
So we're basically starting at 0, y 120, virtual width alignment,
然后我们把它放在中心
and then we're centering it.
所以我们需要改变的最后一件事
So the one last piece of that that we need to change
处于标题屏幕状态 而不是直接进入播放状态
is in our title screen state, instead of going straight to a play state
在第15行 我们将进入倒计时状态
here on line 15, we're going to a countdown state.
这样做的效果是 如果我们进入鸟10号
And what this has the effect of doing, if we go into bird10,
就是当我们按回车键时 注意我们要走三 二 一
is when we press Enter, notice that we're going three, two, one,
然后进入我们的游戏状态
then going into our play state.
不仅仅是直接进入播放状态
Not just going straight into the play state
和以前一样 给我们的用户一点时间喘口气
as before, giving our user a little bit of time to catch their breath.
如果我们死了 我们就会进入得分状态 但一旦我们按下Enter键
And then if we die, we go to our score state, but once we press Enter,
请注意 我们也在这样做
notice we're doing that as well.
因此 在我们的得分状态下 我们也将切换到倒计时状态
So in our score state, we also are changing to the countdown state.
这就是如何建立一个倒计时状态
So that was how to make a countdown state.
在这些例子中 可能我最喜欢的部分 就是这个例子
Probably my favorite part of many of these examples, and of this example
也是将音频添加到我们的应用程序中
as well, is adding audio to our application.
音乐和音效 这真的将一切联系在一起
Music and sound effects, which really ties everything together.
所以我们要继续 看看这个
So we're going to go ahead and take a look at this.
这很简单
It's very simple.
和我们上周学到的非常相似 甚至是我们刚练乒乓球的时候
Very similar to what we learned last week, even when we just did Pong.
因此 在Bird11的主要流星中 这就是我们现在要看到的
So in main.lua of bird11, which is what we're going to look at now,
我们要看一张音表
we're going to take a look at a table of sounds
我们已经在第88行进行了初始化
that we've initialized on line 88.
我们已经给了他们所有的钥匙
We've given them all keys.
跳跃 爆炸 受伤 得分
Jump, explosion, hurt, score.
这些都是我用BFX程序生成的音效
These are all sound effects that I've generated with the BFX program
如果你还记得的话 我们上周用过的
that we used last week, if you recall.
然后是我在网上找到的一首音乐曲目
And then a music track that I found online
在免费声音上 这是免费使用的
on FreeSound, which is free to use.
如果好奇的话 这里有联系
The link is here, if curious.
这只是一个很好的 快乐的配乐 我发现这个游戏
It's just a nice, happy soundtrack that I found for this game.
在第99行到第100行 我们要做一个额外的步骤
On line 99 to 100, we're going to do one additional step
在我们开始音乐之前
before we start the music.
我们要将循环设置为true
We're going to set looping on that to true
因为在这样的无限博弈中
because in games that are infinite like this,
我们不想让我们的音乐就这么走了 然后突然停止
we don't want our music to just go, and then stop abruptly.
我们想让它循环播放
We want to have it loop.
将循环设置为true
Set looping to true.
我实际上是在我们任何一个州之外开始演奏这种音乐的
I actually begin the play of that music outside of any of our states
因为这将是一个全球性的音乐轨道 然后这就是音乐
because it's going to be a global music track, and then that's the music.
我们还需要音效
We also need sound effects.
如果我们看一下鸟的档案第45行
If we look in our bird file here line 45, which
我们有跳跃的逻辑
is where we have the logic for jumping, we're
同时播放我们生成的跳跃音效
also playing the jump sound effect that we've generated.
另外 在我们的游戏状态下 如果我们看一下那里
Additionally, in our play state, if we take a look there,
我们可以在这里的州文件夹中查看
we can go ahead and see in our states folder here.
去玩状态 看看第58行
Go to play state, and take a look at line 58.
这是我们得分的地方
This is where we score a point.
所以我们应该在这里播放配乐音效 简单地说
So we should play our score sound effects here, simply put.
然后在第80到81行也是一样的
And then the same thing on line 80 to 81,
碰撞 这里的声音效果 实际上我们
collide, the sound effect here, which is we're actually
把两个声音叠加在一起 这是很常见的
layering two sounds on top of each other, which is a common thing
在声音设计和游戏设计中的应用
to do in sound design, and game design.
一个声音 往往是不是所有你需要完成一个特定的效果
One sound, often, isn't all you need to accomplish a particular effect.
所以我听到了爆炸声 这是一种白噪音效果
So I have an explosion sound, which is kind of a white noise effect,
然后是一种伤害的声音效果 有点像向下的正弦波
and then a hurt sound effect, which is sort of like a downward sine wave
声音的类型
type of sound.
95到96年的情况也是一样
It would be the exact same here on 95 to 96.
一旦我们把所有这些拼在一起 我们就可以开始了
Once we put all these pieces together, we're going to run bird11.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
我们有音乐
We get music.
[哔哔声]
[BEEPING]
我们得到一个跳跃的声音效果
We get a jump sound effect.
当我们得了一分
And when we score a point,
[叮]
[DING]
我们得到了另一种声音效果
we get another sound effect.
[碰撞]
[CRASH]
如果我们碰到一个管道 请注意
And then if we hit a pipe, notice that we have a sort of
[模仿噪音]
[MIMICS NOISE]
和白噪声或爆炸效果叠加在一起
and a white noise or an explosion effect layered together.
所以这就把所有的东西都结合在一起了 创造性的和艺术性的
So that sort of brings everything together, creatively and artistically.
作为对观众的练习 在bird12中
As an exercise to the viewer, in bird12--
在GitHub存储库中 我们有一些代码
in the GitHub repo, we have some code that
允许您实际将鼠标点击添加到Flappy Bird
allows you to actually add mouse clicks to the Flappy Bird
为了让它更像真正的游戏
in order to make it a little bit more like the actual game, which
是一款iOS游戏
was an iOS game.
所以它依赖于水龙头
So it relied on taps.
您可能想要使用的功能是Love 鼠标按下x y 按钮
The function that you might want to use is love.mousepressed x, y, button,
我鼓励你们思考我们是如何接受意见 并做出
and I would encourage you to think about how we took input, and made
在我们前面的一个例子中 它在键盘的上下文中是全局的
it global in the context of a keyboard in one of our earlier examples
所以我们可以称之为 这是在我们的Bird.Lua文件中按下的鼠标
so that we can call this was the mouse just pressed in our bird.lua file,
而不是主文件
as opposed to the main file.
因此 下一次 我们将介绍一些新概念
And so next time, we're going to be covering a few new concepts.
或者精灵床单
Or sprite sheets.
所以拿出一个大的图像文件 然后取出其中的一大块
So taking a large file of images, and taking out chunks of that
因此 我们不必拥有一百万个图形文件
so we don't have to have a million graphic files.
程序布局
Procedural layouts.
这将在游戏Breakout的背景下进行
This will be in the context of the game Breakout.
所以我们想要在我们的游戏中铺开所有的砖块 在程序上
So we want to lay out all the bricks in our game, procedurally,
在某种程度上 我们在程序上
in sort of the same way that we've procedurally
在这个游戏中创造了一个管道水平线
created a pipe level in this game.
我们将讨论不同的级别 并拥有
We'll be talking about separate levels, and having
它们存储在内存中 而不是只有一个连续的级别
them stored in memory as opposed to just one continuous level.
我们将谈论健康问题
We'll be talking about health.
我们将讨论粒子系统 它正在催生小迷你
We'll be talking about particle systems, which is spawning little mini
图形来实现其他方式很难捕捉的各种效果
graphics to accomplish various effects that are otherwise difficult to capture
在简单的精灵动画中
in simple sprite animation.
基于输入的碰撞检测稍微更花哨一点
A little bit fancier collision detection based on input
这样我们就能以我们想要的方式驱动球的行为
so that we can drive ball behavior the way we want to,
然后还永久保存数据
and then also persistent save data.
我们怎么能拿到高分 而不是
How can we take a high score, and not have
每次我们运行应用程序时 它都会刷新为0 但会将其保存到磁盘
it refresh to 0 every time we run the application, but rather save it to disk
所以以后每次运行程序时 我们都可以看到
so that every time you run the program thereafter, we can see
我们在过去几天里得到的分数
what we've gotten scored in days past.
第一个赋值 或其他第二个赋值 赋值一
The first assignment, or other the second assignment, assignment one,
会比过去几周稍微复杂一些
is going to be a little bit more complicated than last weeks,
但仍相当可行
but still fairly doable.
让管道间隙稍微随机一些 这是其中的第一个组成部分
Make pipe gaps slightly random, being the first component of this.
因此 以前 管道间隙被设置为常量值
So before, a pipe gap was set to a constant value.
也许让它成为某种随机值
Maybe make it some sort of random value.
管道间距也是如此
Pipe intervals as well.
所以我们每隔两秒就产卵一次
So we're spawning every two seconds.
也许我们想要改变这一点 制造管道
Maybe we want to change that up, make pipes
产卵略有不同 更零星一些
spawn a little differently, a little more sporadically.
这项任务的更复杂的方面
The more complicated aspect of this assignment
将根据运动员的表现授予他们一枚奖牌
is going to be awarding players a medal based on their performance.
所以可能会有一枚铜牌、一枚银牌和一枚金牌--
So have maybe a bronze, a silver, and a gold medal--
除了他们的分数外 您还可以在分数屏幕中显示的图像
an image that you display in the score screen in addition to just their score
只是为了给他们一点个人反馈
just to give them a little bit of personal feedback,
让他们觉得自己的努力是有回报的 并让他们
and make them feel rewarded for their effort, and make them
争取拿到最后一块奖牌
strive to get that last medal.
最后 您将实现暂停功能 我们已经讨论过了
And then lastly, you'll implement a pause feature, which we talked about
例如 当你按下p键时 游戏就会停止
in class, so that when you press, for example, the key p, the game will stop.
但与这个例子不同的是 当我们再次按p时
But unlike that example, when we press p again,
比赛应该继续进行 就像它之前的状态一样
the game should resume just as it was in its prior state.
所以 Flappy Bird就是这样了
So that will be it for Flappy Bird.
下次再见了
I'll see you guys next time.
非常感谢
Thanks a lot.